Chapter 4: A Really Big Supermarket

AN/1: I'm still working out a more regular posting schedule, it might have to be once every two weeks.

AN/2: Here's something that was edited out in the first chapter that was meant to go just before Ozland's bit: imgur dot com slash HXZNHCY

#######
CHAPTER FOUR
#######

THE BURROW, DOOR 74, 1183 DIAGON ALLEY, INSIDE A DIMENSIONAL SOMETHING THAT WASN'T EXPLAINED PROPERLY, LONDON

"We had to move from Ottery St Catchpole during the War," Mrs Weasley said, slightly stiffly, "there wasn't enough time to find a universe-fragment with a moon in it. Anyway," she brightened, "take care of yourselves, Albus, Minerva." They nodded, and disappeared in a puff of displaced air.

She turned back to Ozland. "Want some lunch before we head out?"

The Burrow, as Ozland found out it was called, made for a welcome respite from the lunacy of wizarding Britain. As long as he avoided looking out the windows at the vast, ancient craters that pockmarked the rolling English countryside around them like the bullet-holes of a target on an interplanetary firing range, he could almost convince himself that there was really nothing wrong at all, and that he hadn't been whisked here — a pocket dimension, or something (Ozland still wasn't really completely clear on that bit) — by a 120-year-old magical Headmaster after jumping through a puddle.

Mrs Weasley had done the introductions for Mr Weasley, Ron, Ginny, Fred, and George in turn. There had been some brief confusion over Fred and George, with Fred insisting that he was George, and George insisting that he was Fred, until Mrs Weasley demanded that they show their birthmarks, and it had turned out that they had Apparated into one another's seats while nobody was looking.

Mr Weasley and Ron had immediately bombarded him with questions, and after he'd answered (shortly and vaguely), Fred or George would follow it up with some unexpected question that threw him completely off-balance every time — all the while with Ginny staring sullenly into the depths of her plate, as if the act of staring would reveal to her the answer to an ancient cosmic riddle carefully hidden within the strewn-about pieces of carrot and parsley.

Eventually the twins seemed to grow bored with asking nonsensical follow-up questions, and started adding their own answers after Ozland had finished. It usually went like this:

Ron: So – is it really true everyone in New Zealand has to wear ground-harnesses or else they fall into the Sun?

Ozland: No. Um, at least, I don't think —

Fred (confidently): Of course not, Ronald. The Sun faces away from the Southern Hemosphere.

Ozland (cautiously): Right now it's not, if that's what you mean. It does in daytime.

Fred (even more confidently): Exactly, when the Sun does face the Southern Hemisphere, the Moon's on the other side so it always cancels out the gravity.

Ron (dubiously): Wouldn't that just make you weightless?

George: Not if you wear really heavy boots.

He had made sure to wolf down the rest of his food (a slice of beef pie and pumpkin juice) as quickly as possible, which, quite cunningly, ensured that his mouth was full the whole time, rendering him unable to answer any questions.

Mr Weasley shook his hand vigorously after lunch had concluded. "Delightful talking to you, Ozland. And do try see what you can do about getting to the bottom of this thermos business, eh?"

Ozland hummed noncommittally. (Mr Weasley had asked earlier how thermoses could keep hot things hot and cold things cold, and he'd muttered something about heat conduction without admitting he didn't actually know.)

Mrs Weasley called from outside, her voice carrying through the house. "Time to go! Chop chop!"

The twins Apparated immediately, Ginny had already bolted out the door some time ago, and Ron was quickly finishing off the rest of the pie, wiping his mouth on his sleeve.

"Er, hey mate," he began awkwardly, as Ozland reached the doorway, "sorry for all the questions back then - I'm not that stupid," Ozland had been thinking 'gullible' maybe, but not 'stupid' - but Ron seemed intent on preemptively defending himself, "it's just, you know, with the twins it's always easier just to play along when they're doing their comedy routine." He visibly reddened.

"Uh, no worries," replied Ozland, a little warily, "I guess it's refreshing to be the one answering questions instead of asking them." He waited for Ron, and they started walking to the outhouse which lead out of the Weasley's universe-pocket-thing (he really needed to get the mechanics of it explained to him sometime). "So," he said, "your brothers - they just Apparated, right?" Note to self: brush up on small-talk.

Ron nodded. If he'd been aware of the clumsiness of the prompt, he gave no indication. "Ever since they got their licenses last year they haven't walked more than a yard. Well," he said, reflectively, "they do sometimes, for the novelty. We'll have to wait until Seventh Year before the lessons, though," he added, preempting Ozland's question. There was something very earnest and carefree about the way he spoke that Oz couldn't help but begin to warm to him.

"Ah." Outside, he was reminded of Mrs Weasley's oddly stiff reaction to his question about the lack of a moon in their universe-pocket. He had the feeling that he really shouldn't be tugging at this particular thread, but it was also bothering him immensely. "Weird question, but I asked your mum about there being no moon in the sky - and she said that you guys had to move quickly - "

The red-head looked distinctly uncomfortable.

"Uh, you don't have to - "

"It's not really something we talk about," Ron said, quietly. "But I don't want you to think it was anything really bad, at least not worse than all the things that happened in the War." He exhaled. "Mum says Charlie was tortured under the Cruciatus until he told the Death Eaters where we lived. We had a half-hour to find a universe, cut out a fragment, put the house in it, and shove it in an internally-expanded rucksack. Bill says it's a wonder he managed to find somewhere with air, let alone a moon, in the time he had. He blames the whole thing on Dumbledore, for some reason, but mum's never been able to get him to tell us why."

"Charlie and Bill would be your - ?"

"Older brothers, yeah."

They were nearing the door to the outhouse now - Mrs Weasley was passing out long scrolls of paper to Ginny and the twins, seeming to scold them for some reason, although Ozland couldn't make out the words.

"Was Charlie . . . okay?" Why am I even asking that?

Ron looked at him strangely. "'Course, but, you know, he was a bit different after."

Professor McGonagall's words echoed in his head. The Death Eaters, they were his followers . . . We're still recovering . . . "Jesus, I'm sorry about that."

"Not your fault, mate. And who's Jezars?"

That broke up the mood a little. Ozland coughed. "Um, just a Moggley saying."

"Muggle."

"Oh, yeah. Muggle."

#######

"Right," Mrs Weasley said, with the air of a military general. "Ron, here's your list, you'll be teamed up with Ginny today." She handed Ron an unlabelled can. "Remember - use the everlasting baked beans to leave a trail, just in case you get lost - and if the store closes before you get out - "

"Stay put, cover myself in cooked chicken to stay warm, don't rely on the Compass Charm, got it," Ron said, vacantly, looking over his list before leaving with Ginny.

The first entrance to the Supermarket had been discovered, or created, or something by Giannis Slarkensson in 1973, and at that point, it was a small door, big enough only for a House Elf, with single turnstile. It could still be found along Side-Side Alley HNT-R2 – a mostly deserted street, which was itself the product of another magical accident – a fractal Geminio Curse cast by a disgruntled land developer.

Since then, the Supermarket had almost metastasised all across Diagon Alley. Mrs Weasley said you could usually tell if a new Supermarket entrance was emerging by the lumpy, organic protrusions it made in the sides of buildings and cobblestone streets, before bubbling out into a set of revolving doors. There had been an article in The Quibbler about a woman who found an entrance to the Supermarket under her armpit, although apparently the evidence for that one was tenuous.

They had gone through the nearest entrance which was in one of the stalls in the men's bathroom of Borghill's Birdbath Boutique (there seemed to be a general alliterative trend with the naming schema, Ozland had noticed), and had come out, the blue-tinted light and chill air washing over them, between two freezers full of frozen peas, frozen kebabs and cheesecakes.

As they walked down the rows of freezers, he hadn't been able to stop himself from gawping – he'd never really seen anything like it before. After the economic collapse of the seventies, either you knew people who knew people who could smuggle two metric tonnes of salad dressing through the Trans-Pacific Railway, or you whipped up homemade salad dressing with vinegar, white paint, and dilute nitric acid. There was something ravishingly beautiful about its cold, sterile regularity. Consume me, it beckoned. Devour me, feast on me -

He reached towards a small strawberry cheesecake, and the voice abruptly stopped.

Hold on, I think there's a sensible thing to ask in this situation. But for the life of me, I can't – oh, that's it.

"Um, Mrs Weasley? Is this like a test of character or something? I'm not going to, say, eat this cheesecake, and then be turned into a cheesecake?"

"Heavens, no. Whatever you want, you can take it. It's all free," she replied, preoccupied with scribbling illegible words onto the shopping list.

"And the price is, you know, really nothing, rather than pieces of my soul or anything like that?"

"Nothing but your waistline."

The voice started again as he cautiously bit into the cheesecake. Yes, eat up, boy. Take another.

"Mrs Weasley," he said mildly, "there's a voice in my head telling me to eat up and take another cheesecake."

Nothing dodgy or sinister going on around here, the voice said hurriedly, purely altruistic motives. You just look a bit thin, that's all.

"Um, it's telling me I look a bit thin."

Mrs Weasley glanced at him, then returned to her list. "You do look a bit thin."

See?, said the voice, with a touch of indignance.

Well, thought Ozland, I've never seen a newspaper with the title 'Man Saves Twenty Drowning Orphans, Builds Hospital, Helps At Homeless Shelter: Says A Voice In His Head Told Him To Do It'.

Well, the voice said with scorn, at least you're halfway acknowledging that you're irrationally prejudiced against disembodied voices, not many people are mature enough to do that.

Oh come on! Ozland couldn't really think of any other responses.

You enjoyed that cheesecake, but you're denying yourself the joy of eating another cheesecake, just because you got told to by a disembodied voice, the voice continued, seemingly amused. Do you need to hear 'Simon says' before you do anything? Take a look at that blueberry cheesecake over there, for instance - the company went out of business in 1968 in your world, so I found a world where they didn't. Luxury cheesecakes. Artisan cheesecakes. Full-cream milk, real blueberries. They used to go for fifty pounds a –

Out out OUT, get out of my head, RIGHT now.

Alright, alright, the voice said, clearly wounded, I'll just –

"Ah, Ozland," Mrs Weasley tapped her cheek, "you'll go with Fred and George. And if they get up to any funny stuff, make sure to tell me," she added, lowering her voice.

"Fred, George," she shouted at the twins (George was shoulder-deep in salted macadamia nuts, and Fred was egging him on to go deeper), "Ozland's coming with you, and in Merlin's name, if he gets lost, it's on you two to explain to Headmaster Dumbledore."

George dusted himself off, licking each of his fingers. "He won't get lost – "

" – unless he, you know, gets lost."

George turned to Fred. "That was a decent pun, and it's your fault for messing up the execution."

"Mrs Weasley, is this really something I should risk coming along for?" asked Ozland, who was beginning to reconsider the shopping trip.

"Young man, it's no more dangerous than any other infinite supermarket - so long as you don't go past the butter with the purple spots and treat the disembodied voice in your head with respect and give thoughtful consideration to whatever it says - " (How odd, Ozland thought, her lips were weirdly out of sync when she said that last bit) " - and I promised Albus we'd keep an eye on you, so that's that." She checked her watch. "Ten past twelve, we're making good time. Be back here within the hour – and if it takes any longer, remind Fred and George to send a Patronus."

Fred and George waved goodbye. As soon as she was gone, they whipped out their wands, and, after doing a few complicated swirly motions, tapped them to the ground and to one another's shoulders, and said "Olenduvõrknit" in synchrony. Ozland watched, fascinated, as a red thread appeared, linking all the places that they'd touched, swaying gently like spider silk. As they began walking, the thread extended itself.

"That's one of ours – " said Fred.

" – so keep it to yourself. We can trust you, right?"

"I can barely remember it!" Ozland protested, struggling to keep up (the Weasley twins were rather taller than him).

"Some child of prophecy," George murmured, grinning.

"Wait, what?"

"Dumbledore didn't tell you?" said Fred.

"Um, he might have suggested it really subtly but no he didn't tell me."

"Then if he didn't tell you, you oughtn't to know and you'll probably find out later," remarked Fred sensibly.

"We could tell you," George added, "but it'd mess up the fabric of reality, and the Ministry'll fine us a hundred Galleons for that if we do it again."

They came to a stop beside a row of edible roses. "Anyway," Fred interrupted Ozland before he could respond, "it's simple. Hold out your wand."

Ozland held out his wand.

"No, not like that you twonk."

Ozland held out his wand differently.

"Yes, just like that. Now all you have to do is a fixed – by that I mean keep your wrist in the same place – twirl widdershins – counterclockwise, if you like – twice – doesn't matter how quick, then stab at the centre of your wand-circle, do a wiggly zig-zag thing down the middle, inside your wand-circle – that bit's not actually too important so just do it however you want – and say 'olenduvõrknit'. You have to pronounce that really precisely – the 'o' in the 'duvõrk' isn't like a normal 'o' – you have to round your lips like an 'o', but you have to keep your tongue up – but not touching the roof of your mouth – just near your teeth. Syllable-stress doesn't matter."

Ozland went over the motions in his head. "Um, why do I have to be the one do this?"

Fred and George looked at one another, and then Fred casually brought out a small velvety box, snapping it open. Everything around them went utterly silent, as if the box was sucking in all the noise. "Alright," he said, "this is a Secret Box. Anything we say when it's open stays secret between whoever hears it, and if you can't give it away. By 'can't', I mean you really don't want to find out what happens if you try to. That includes what we're saying right now. So just to be sure, we have a Secret Box, you know what a Secret Box is and how to cast the spell we outlined before, and we did something other than efficiently find all of the things on the shopping list, engage you in friendly conversation, and come back as soon as we could."

That's actually incredibly powerful. "But why do I have to – "

"Because it's a soul-tracer which only works for your own soul," said Fred, grimly, snapping shut the Box.

"I don't get why you need that to be a secret," Ozland said, puzzled.

"Accio calamari," Fred enunciated, and a packet of squid flew from the air and into his hands. "Unregistered soul magic is twenty years in Azkaban. It's daft, and I won't say any more. Now remember – fixed twirl, twice clockwise, centre-stab, zig-zag down the middle, 'o-len-du-võrk-nit' – "

" – with the tongue up for the 'o' sound in 'vork'. Got it, lemme just visualise it first." Ozland listed out the sequence in his head, then did it again, and then for a third time. He held out his wand, closed his eyes, imagined his wand, imagined his hand moving with the wand. Fixed twirl, twice clockwise, centre-stab, zig-zag down the middle. He almost shouted the incantation in his head.

For some reason, he felt oddly exhilarated, but breathless, at the same time. "Okay, right. Now I'll do it for real."

Fred and George were staring at him, standing stock-still. "Merlin," Fred murmured. "No wand movement, no words." He coughed. "Right, well, just tap it to the ground and you're sorted."

Ozland complied, confused. A purplish line appeared. "What does it mean?"

George scratched his chin. "Casting a spell, with no wand movement and no words – it's not unheard of. But it's spiffing stuff, you know."

"Could be the concentrated ambient magic," Fred said without conviction. "Anyway, we've got fifty minutes left so we're going to have to hurry. Skappakurg." A plaited basket popped into existence in his hands.

They broke into a jogging pace, twisting and turning around corners, with Fred and George saying 'Accio everything on the shopping list' at regular intervals. The Supermarket was a labyrinth, and Ozland realised what Mrs Weasley had meant when she warned the twins about him getting lost.

The items on the shelves began to look less and less familiar – Ozland passed by an entire section of candied spiders (Fred and George grabbed a few, "for Ron", they said, without elaboration), whale-meat on a stick, floating colourful pyramids, and then –

"Jesus fucking Christ."

"What?" said Fred and George simultaneously.

Ozland was standing in front of an entire shelf of chocolate. "What do you mean 'what?' – do you know how much this is all worth?" he said, incredulously. "Oh, unless this isn't real cocoa – that would make sense." He picked up a packet, turning over to the ingredients. He shook his head. "No way. No fucking way."

Fred turned to his counterpart. "He's gone bonkers," he said, shaking his head. "No, really – what's the deal? It's just chocolate."

He looked at them, flabbergasted, and began shoving as many as he could into his jacket and pants. "This is eighty percent cocoa – bullion standard."

"Absolutely certifiable," muttered George, audibly. "We in range?"

Fred pulled out a walkie-talkie. There was a hiss of static. "Not yet."

Ozland ignored them, using a pen-knife to slice holes into his jacket so that he could stuff in a few more bars. By the time he'd finished, a quarter of his body-weight was in chocolate, and Fred and George were nothing but trailing red threads. It would be annoying and embarrassing, but if he could lug them home, it would easily be worth it - 'it' meaning some ridiculous amount of money. He picked up one, idly looking at the purple packaging. "Rowntree," he read aloud, totally unnecessarily. His voice echoed slightly.

Tearing off the wrapping and biting into the chocolate, he started running after the Weasley twins' trail. Mystery solved — the Supermarket gets its stock from parallel universes or something.

He stopped, panting. Around him were what looked like TV dinners, but instead of chicken and potato and greens, there were bricks. Just a single brick, wrapped in plastic, in each one — covered in gravy. The language looked vaguely like Hebrew.

The section after it was filled with thirty-foot-long tentacles, frozen and bound together with rope. Jesus, why the hell are Fred and George way out here?

Ozland walked further, straining his ears, hearing a voice from not very far. "Fantastic ideas as always, Gred and Forge. As soon as we get ahold of a thousand-tonne block of stone, we'll try it out." There was a pause, interrupted by strange insectile clicking sounds. "Good to hear it, mate. Now, to hold up our end of the deal . . . "

He peeked around the next shelf, seeing a circular clearing that eventually branched out into six different paths. Fred stood in the middle. Up to one ear, he held a walkie-talkie. Out of the other, a snake-like wire that terminated in what looked to be a record player, except with a dictionary instead of a vinyl disc. George was rummaging through another shelf, looking intrigued.

" . . . and when the prankee opens the door, the bucket of water falls onto them, getting them soaking wet. Brilliant stuff, innit?" Another burst of insectile clicking sounds. The dictionary flung open, pages flicking back and forth in a blur of paper. "Yeah, we thought so too." More clicks and more pages. "Okay, you two take care. Always a pleasure. Bye." George turned off the walkie-talkie. "Suckers. Fred, what's your estimate?"

"About five thousand leagues north-north-west," said Fred. "We could probably take apart one of dad's cars, get all the pieces through the door, rebuild it, stock up on concentrated thaumic fluid, and be there and back in a week . . . and we've got ten minutes left - shite, we can still make it back."

George pulled out the wire from his ear, twirled his wand, and the dictionary-record-player began folding in on itself like an origami city struck by an earthquake.

At the same time, Fred pulled out a long roll of what looked like a Persian carpet from his right pocket, throwing it out with a flourish. It floated above the floor, quite steadily, and Fred and George jumped on, lying belly-down. "Oi, Ozland, get on and hold on."

Ozland tentatively stepped onto the carpet, which rippled underneath him, lying down and holding onto the front. "Jesus, is this is a flying carpet?"

As Fred and George stroked and patted it, murmuring encouraging words, the carpet slowly began lifting up into the air, before accelerating forward. Oz realised hadn't really been able to appreciate what 'infinite' meant until he saw the gray horizon all around him. "Oi, don't hold onto the front - that's for steering," said George. Ozland obediently grabbed onto the fur. "And to answer your question, no." George rolled over, digging into his pockets, before taking out the Secret Box again. His face was mischievous as he opened the lid. The roar of wind around them stopped, although he could still feel it on his face. "We applied a broomstick Charm while it was all rolled up, and it worked. So you could say it was a carpet which we tricked into thinking was a broomstick. Real flying carpets bend the space-time continuum around them to move around, that's how you tell." He closed the Box, and the wind resumed.

#######

Mrs Weasley had been suspicious, but Ozland hadn't given any indication of anything out-of-the-ordinary happening, although his definition of 'ordinary' had been adjusted substantially.

Out in the birdbath store, he reluctantly handed over the chocolate to her to keep in her expanded purse, and in the process of looking through all of his pockets, he noticed that, nestled snugly in his sleeve, was a blueberry cheesecake.

#######

Madam Malkin's was fairly ordinary apart from the self-animated measuring tapes — but then again, the Supermarket had also been fairly ordinary, apart from the fact that it was infinitely large, and tried to telepathically convince him to eat more cheesecakes.

Ozland tuned into the various voices drifting across the stalls next to him.

"Look, Hagrid," came one voice, "what about the Dark Lords from Ilvermorny, or Beauxbatons, or Durmstrang, or for that matter, the Comintern Magic Academy — all I'm saying," the voice went conciliatory, "is that the statement 'All Dark Lords came from Slytherin', let alone 'You'll become a Dark Lord if you go to Slytherin' is subject to, uh, Anglocentric bias."

"Aye, I can see tha'," came a much gruffer voice.

"And, you know," the other voice rushed on, "how many Dark Lords have there been, anyway? Not many, I'll bet. There's simply not enough data to draw sweeping conclusions like that — it would be like, um, say I had two goldfish, and say one of them dies, and the next day, there's a war in the Middle-East. And then another one dies a few years later, and there's another war in the Middle-East. Does that mean the deaths of my goldfish have anything to do with war in the Middle-East? Well, only two goldfish have died — that's nowhere near enough goldfish to draw any conclusions about any correlations between the deaths of goldfish and wars in the Middle-East. Or let's pretend that it really is the case that going to Slytherin, say, triples your likelihood of becoming a Dark Lord — if the prior probability is, um, six Dark Lords in the past five hundred years, and there've been twenty-five thousand Hogwarts students, that just means the likelihood of becoming a Dark Lord only went from 0.24% to 0.72%. 'Triple' might sound huge, but in reality it only means the likelihood of that student becoming a Dark Lord increased by 0.48% and that's tiny — does any of this make sense?"

There was a long pause.

"No."

"Ah, forget it then. How does this sound: I'll try and not end up in Slytherin — and if I do, I'll try to not become a Dark Lord."

"An' if yeh become a Dark Lord?"

" . . . I'll be nice to my enemies, minimise casualties, and abide by international law?"

Nothing else noteworthy happened in the store.

#######

The bookstore was also mostly ordinary, in the way that Ozland had come to realise was the case for most of wizarding Britain. Once you got down to it, it was just people jumping through puddles and wearing silly pointy hats. The fact that none of it made an ounce of sense didn't really matter. A firm principle Ozland had abided by ever since he'd thought of it an hour ago, was that if something in the world didn't make any sense to him, it was him at fault, not the world. All he knew for certain was that somehow it all worked out, that he'd figure out the specifics later, and that he'd use the specifics to either take over the universe or settle down somewhere and become a dentist in Surrey.

"Apparently some of the books here scream and bite you if you open them the wrong way," remarked a girl, who'd politely shook his hand and introduced herself as Hermione Granger. She'd been going through a reference book of some sort, with the titles of other reference books in them, neatly inscribing numbers between 1 and 3,856 beside them in red felt — presumably in the order she was planning to read them. They were in the middle of a long, partly-lit corridor with bookshelves on either side.

"Cats do that too," Ozland said, feeling quite stupid.

She frowned. "If you open them the wrong way?"

"Well, I'd think so."

"Mhm," she mhm'd, turning back to her meta-reference book.

"Honestly," Ozland began, who'd been struck by a burning desire to say something else absurd, "anyone who opens a book the wrong way deserves to be screamed at and bitten, in my opinion."

"What if it took their fingers off?" said the girl rather nonchalantly, without pausing.

Ozland doubled down. "Even if it took their whole hand off. Their whole arm, even."

She marked down '486', and then scribbled it out, writing '487' instead. A flash of annoyance passed over her face. "Where does it go, do you think?"

"Where does what go?"

"The finger-pieces. Do you suppose it has a book-stomach to digest them?"

"I suppose," supposed Ozland. "But then again, I suppose it could just spit them out. Or maybe," he supposed further, with a speculative air, "the book absorbs the finger-pieces as new material, turning them into extra chapters, or adding unnecessary words to sentences to make the book longer."

"Maybe," said the girl (from her tone, Ozland couldn't tell if she was being genuine or viciously mocking him), "maybe the font just gets larger and larger until they end up in the large print section."

"Then all the large print books would be covered in blood, wouldn't they?"

"Some of them are covered in blood." She flicked over to another page.

"Oh." That's a bit worrying.

"Professor McGonagall says the defense mechanism instills healthy respect for books."

Ozland leaned back against the bookshelf behind him, but felt it come unbalanced, even though it was, itself, leaning against a wall, and hastily straightened himself in the hope that he hadn't caused any permanent structural damage. "Ah, you've met her, then?"

"She introduced me to," she waved her hand about, "all of this, just a few hours ago, actually."

. . .

"That can't be right," said Ozland automatically, his grip on normalcy beginning to loosen, "um, unless by a few hours ago you mean only after twelve. Dumbledore said they were dealing with a Type Three something-or-other at Hogwarts so they needed to dash, and that's why they left me with the Weasleys at twelve."

The girl looked up from her book for the first time in ten minutes. "Well I'm not sure who you were talking to," she said, evidently thinking it over, "because she came over to my house at eleven, we left Ollivanders at eleven thirty, Madam Malkins finished the measurements for my robes at twelve . . . and it was twelve thirty when we finished buying a trunk, and twelve forty-five when we finished buying Potions equipment, and well, she left me here about a quarter of an hour ago saying she needed a good drink, and said she'd be back within the hour."

Ozland buried his face in his hands. "Just when I thought I'd figured everything out. Oh, hold on. No, it's obvious: she has a sister who's also a Professor and also teaches at Hogwarts. There we go, no time-travel shenanigans necessary."

Hermione opened her mouth to reply just as Professor McGonagall appeared around the corner, striding down the corridor and tutting. "Really, young lady — "

"Um, Professor – " began Ozland.

She stopped, and raised her eyebrows. "Do I know you?"

"Yes," said Ozland, who was mildly confused at this new development, "you introduced me to the wizarding world a few hours ago. Shouldn't you be dealing with the Type Three florkpurple superintelligence thing at Hogwarts? It sounded fairly serious."

Professor McGonagall looked alarmed. "Who did you hear that from?"

"Dumbledore."

"And when did you hear it?"

"Twelve o'clock today," he answered, frustratedly, "when you two left me at the Weasleys." The thought occurred to him that he could be speaking to Professor McGonagall's body-double.

"Ah," said Professor McGonagall, seeming even more alarmed. She turned to Hermione. "I'll just be a few moments more, dear, and then we'll go and fetch your Astronomy equipment," she said, before suddenly disappearing.

"That," said Ozland, "was weird as hell."

Hermione nodded in the very abstracted way that people doing numbers in their head do. "Ye-es."

He coughed. "Anyway, I've got all my books, so I'd best be going. I guess we'll, um, see one another at Hogwarts."

She looked mildly disappointed for some reason. "Alright."

Ozland tripped on an uneven bit of carpet as he made his way down the corridor.

#######

The main area of the bookstore was thick with people, all of whom seemed to be ecstatically clamouring around, well, something or someone. It was difficult to say, in the same way that it would be difficult to say what a given whirlpool was whirling around. The screaming and bursts of light suggested two possibilities: either that someone was a celebrity being assaulted by photographers, or a central figure in a civil war which had recently erupted between Horticulture and Self-Help. Everything was humid and loud, and it was no wonder Hermione had chosen to escond herself in a section, which, to Ozland's knowledge, only had the reference volumes of every book that could ever exist in alphabetical order, except that the publishers had stopped at Volume QMXIIX due to poor sales. The one he'd picked up had started with the fascinating title of 'aaaaabaaaaa by aa' and, after a couple thousand pages, ended with the even more fascinating-sounding 'aaaaabbghlk by qz'. (It was useful if you already knew what book you were looking for, but not much else — which went a long way toward explaining the lack of foot-traffic. On the other hand, that 'else' was 'a way to torture someone without leaving any physical marks.')

He quickly found Ron, who had relegated himself to the sidelines of whatever was going on, maintaining a wide peopleless space around him by sitting back in an an armchair and holding up to his face a book whose cover read 'Treat Your Own Incurable Infectious Incurable Diseases (Yes, They're Really That Incurable)' in intense green letters.

"Stand back, I have Arcturian whalepox – oh," Ron said, looking at him more closely and putting down the book, "come to get away from Lockhart, too, have you?"

"The author, right?" This was something he was fairly confident about, having passed the rather well-stocked Lockhart Section.

"More than that," Ron went on, sullenly, "he's also a Memory-Charming psycho who got sentenced by the Wizengamot to permanent ravishment – er, banishment – "

" – about to say, permanent ravishment doesn't sound too bad – "

" – so he went to work for the Triad," Ron continued, glaring at him, "and obviously he did dodgy magic stuff with them – 'cos he ended up in the Executer Council and came back ten years later completely off the hook cos' he donated a few hundred thousand Galleons to the Ministry. 'S like everybody's bloody forgotten already. At least, that's what mum says. Oh," he added, as if only suddenly remembering, "and the bugger'll be teaching this year, too. Anyway, we might as well – "

Just then, a hush descended over the bookstore, and a trembling, high-pitched, almost wailing voice reached their ears — it sounded oddly familiar, and by the fifth word, Ozland had nailed down the owner of the voice as Fred (or George, or potentially the third twin, William, who they'd insisted Mr and Mrs Weasley kept in the attic and fed a steady diet of fish-heads). They hadn't heard all of it, since the beginning had been masked by the tremendous noise of the crowd, but the bit they heard went like this: " . . . so you see, it's so, so expensive — the treatments for the non-transmittable version of Arcturian whalepox . . . "

Curiosity piqued (and then some), Ozland and Ron made their way through the crowd, until they could see what was happening. What was happening was . . . he was tempted to say two blonde copies of Ginny had made their way up to a small podium and were posing for photographs with a man who he presumed was Gilderoy Lockhart, but that probably wasn't it, except for the last part.

"And your names?" asked a reporter. (At least, Ozland assumed she was a reporter – if she wasn't a reporter, she was certainly going for a reporter look.)

"Georgina and Frederica Sneasley," said the girls, again in an annoyingly high-pitched voice. One of them coughed, very loudly and very unsubtly, before doubling over and wheezing. A murmur of sympathy went through the crowd.

"Well well well," said the assumed Gilderoy Lockhart, rather magnanimously, "how does this sound? I'll give your family all of the required titles for this year's Defense Against The Dark Arts And Muggle Studies, completely free of - "

"Defense Against The Dark Arts And Muggle Studies?" Ozland hissed to Ron, as the man continued to slather banalities on top of platitudes.

"Yeah," Ron hissed back, "You-Know-Who put a curse on the Defense position a while back, so they keep combining classes and making frogs Professors and doing all sorts of nutty stuff to get it off. Hold on, why are we hissing?"

"I don't know," said Ozland in a normal voice, "it just seemed natural."

" - and might I ask how many of your other siblings are in need of my full book set?"

"Forty," said Georgina Sneasley. "Actually wait, fifty."

A stunned silence followed.

"Just put it in the potato sack, thanks," Frederica Sneasley chimed in.

Lockhart spluttered for a moment, counted out fifty book-sets wrapped in maroon ribbons, placing them one by one into the sack, with a faintly disgusted smile.

As Ozland watched in wonderment, somebody tapped on his shoulder. He turned around, seeing Fred and George.

"So what's all this, then?" said George, looking genuinely curious.

"Um," Ozland looked up to the podium, where the two girls were posing for photographs, "I thought I knew but I'm not sure now."

Ron seemed to have had a similar reaction. He wasn't lost for words — he had all the words, but the order they were supposed to go in seemed to evade him at that moment.

The twins looked just as confused as they were.

"Um," ummed Ozland again, "well, I'll tell you what happened and leave the conjecture out of it." He told them.

"Alright," said Fred. "Seems obvious enough. We pulled off a fantastic prank and conned Lockhart out of hundreds of Galleons' worth of books, Time-Turned back to give ourselves an alibi, and Obliviated one another."

"Or," said George, "we, and by 'we' I mean us, standing here right now, haven't actually done it yet - "

"Wait, what?"

" - but at some point in the future we'll Time-Turn back and do it."

"That . . . " he was about to say 'doesn't make any sense', but there had to be some kind of internally-consistent logic to all of it. "What if you don't do it?"

Fred and George shook their heads. "Honestly, take it from us – "

" – it's best not to go up against the underlying order of reality. Except on Sunday. Besides," George gesticulated in the direction of the two girls, who were taking questions from various journalists, "we've already done it," he grinned, "it'll be a bloody cake-walk."

#######

As they walked through the Trunk Emporium (for Ozland's sake — the Weasleys already had trunks for the most part, and seemed determined to give him advice, as if they were helping him select his first car), Fred and George, having recently morphed from little blonde girls to lanky, red-headed teenagers, filled him on what had happened. "The trick," they'd said, "is leaving it right to the last minute. Then Time gets really desperate and arranges all sorts of weird coincidences."

That time, as they idly walked about in the street outside the bookstore, a broom-rider collided with another broom-rider, causing a brown parcel to fall onto George's head, which contained enough Polyjuice Potion for both of them to maintain a Polyjuiced form for four hours. They realised at that point, that for whatever reason, a strand of Ginny's hair was stuck to Fred's robe, put two and two together, downed the Polyjuice with the hair, and applied the Colour-Changing Charm to their own hair to turn it blonde. Then Fred accidentally spilt some of the Polyjuice on the ground.

The spill pattern spelt out the word 'Arcturian whalepox'.

They spilt some more, and got three paragraphs of detailed instructions.

They spilt even more, and got a sentence reading 'Do this again and I'll sock both of you in the balls.'

The rest, apparently, had gone very well.

"No, not that one."

"Why not that one?" Ozland asked Mrs Weasley for the umpteenth time.

She knelt down, pointing at a series of subtle scratches along the base. "This one's been through at least two owners, or one owner who had it for a while. You can't fix scratches with ordinary repair Charms, you see. Interior expansions degrade over time – if you're not careful, it'll collapse into a singularity with you and your belongings inside."

The trunk salesman, having been busy with someone else up until that moment, stepped in. "An interesting choice, young man," he opened with, before breaking into a well-oiled spiel. "This was Paddaryll Cymeglen's trunk, who worked in the Department of Land Expansions and mapped two hundred universes up until his, er, disappearance. Well-loved and full of adventure, this trunk is."

Ozland's mind had gotten stuck on one particular word. "Disappearance?"

"Oh," said the salesman, airily, "some say he and his belongings collapsed into a singularity, but the rumour going about is he hiccuped during a dimensional ritual and ended up somewhere far off the Charted Zone. In any case, this trunk has been revamped, recharged, and cleaned very thoroughly. And we've had an exorcist come in, just to be sure. Clean in both the material and spiritual realm."

"I think I'll have to pass – "

"And I forgot to add, this certainly isn't an ordinary internally-expanded trunk – "

"They all say that," Mrs Weasley huffed.

" – in fact, it's not an internal expansion at all." He went into a theatrical hush. "Cymeglen made a direct link between our universe and his unregistered house in Cymeglen-551J."

"None of this makes any sense," complained Ozland very quietly. "I just want to buy a trunk and get this over and done with."

Mrs Weasley seemed intrigued. "He did all of this before the passing of the registration laws?" she asked, carefully.

"Indeed."

"And it's eighty Galleons?"

"The same."

She paused. "Is there anything, you know, wrong with Cymeglen-551J?"

"It's eighty fathoms out from the Official Registrar, so you can't be expecting Ministry emergency services, if that's what you mean."

"What's the divergence?" Mrs Weasley demanded.

Ozland folded his arms, glancing around the store. Of all the things I thought I'd be doing today, I wasn't expecting 'buying a universe' to be one of them.

"Something to do with giant potatoes and people speaking Norse. You'll have to Floo the Ministry assessor, I'll send you his details."

Mrs Weasley tapped her cheek. "We'll take a look inside. And it'll have to be forty Galleons."

The salesman looked pained. "Alright, alright."

#######

They'd ended up in a gloomy, dusty room after coming down the stairs, stuffed with old furniture.

Mrs Weasley had murmured what was supposed to be a simple torch Charm, but instead, a faint, pure musical note had rung through the air, grown more and more intense, and then cut off abruptly. After a few seconds of silence, the glassy orbs that they'd noticed before near the ceiling, flickered soundlessly, and then began warmly glowing. She brought out her wand, firing off a series of spells. "Dzevzgalov. Point Me. Löciseng. Alright, we're a mile from the Thames, and North is that way," she said, finally, looking bewildered.

"Potatofind," incanted George. "There's a – "

"That's not a spell," said Ron, stumbling over a pea-green armchair.

"Is too," shot Fred.

" – fifteen-tonne potato under this house."

"Potatofind," said Mrs Weasley, copying his wand-motion. "Merlin, there really is a fifteen-tonne potato underneath . . . underneath the one next to us, too. Mr Forksworth," she said, addressing the salesman, who looked distinctly alarmed, "are you sure you don't remember anything else?"

Mr Forksworth furled his eyebrows in thought. "There was something about a famine, but I'm afraid I'm really not sure. And I'm certain the Ministry assessor talked about vikings — really, you'll have to ask him. By the way," he said, nodding at Ozland, "the house is yours, too. Sixty Galleons?"

"Um, sure – "

"Alright, just sign this, this, and this. Fabulous. And we'll just have to change the blood wards. Aithnedìonffuil." Something in the air in front of Ozland sharpened into an upward curving point, like a glass mountain, becoming more and more distinct until it was a jutting crystal.

"Just reach out and prick your finger on the tip to seal the wards. Give it a strong tap."

Ozland did exactly that, and winced as blood blossomed from his index finger. It seemed to disperse through the air in vivid, roiling curls, giving the whole room a faint red tinge before dissipating.

Mrs Weasley and the salesman congratulated him, and Fred and George clapped him on the back — but he wasn't really paying attention, because he'd just noticed that the room around him was filled with trunks.

#######

Chapter 5: A Cassette

AN/1: okay I have a new schedule where I try to post every two weeks on a Wednesday and even though that hasn't been working out I'll try to stick to it.

AN/2: After this chapter goes up I'll have enough potential plot-hooks to last until the universe reaches thermodynamic equilibrium woohoo

#######

CHAPTER FIVE

#######

The Daily Mail

GALACTIC WHODUNNIT: SCIENTISTS FIND INEXPLICABLE VOID IN UNIVERSE

March 1, 1983

After analysing the latest data from the Rockefeller Wide-Array Moon Telescope, scientists at the Royal Observatory have reported the discovery of a "perfectly spherical void" in the middle of the Virgo Cluster, where matter is not only more sparse, as has been observed in other voids, but "totally absent". The newly-discovered void has been named the Tibbles Void, after the late Walter Rockefeller's cat, who recently came into the possession of his enormous fortune.

Photographs of the edges of the Tibbles Void show galaxies "cleanly bisected", still more torn apart due to an unknown violent cosmic event [...]

#######

Hermione's parents had always enjoyed a good protest – as long as they were small, quiet, and didn't accomplish anything they could indirectly hold responsibility for. This was one of the many areas where Hermione differed from her parents. She'd gone to protests out of an indirect obligation to whales, trees, and elderly people, none of whom presumably could advance their interests without her help.

On the seventh of May 1991, it was drizzling and the grey clouds were milling about in the sky, as if waiting for the weather-police to come along and arrest them for loitering. People were milling about on the ground, setting up stands and hurriedly finishing their placards, waiting for the demonstration to reach critical mass. A homeless man sat at the edge of the water fountain with a newspaper unfolded in his hands. 'FTSE FALLS ANOTHER 2%' – the title had been the same yesterday, and the day before that. Policemen stood at the fringes of the Square, looking uncertain.

"Hermione?" came Anita's voice from behind her.

Everything went into a half-second loop. The pigeons flapped their wings, and flapped them and flapped and flapped. The newspaper turned over in the homeless man's hands, and then jumped back to the start, again and again and again. Everyone around her was walking, and then they were back to were they were, and then they started walking. There was a low buzz that she hadn't noticed before, like ten trillion electronic hornets all descending on her. There was suddenly a second, reddish moon in the sky.

She turned around, but somehow she stayed in the same place because she could see into the back of her head and her squishy, reddish brain like cross-sections had been cut into it with a butcher's knife and her hair flailing about in a loop and she was a big trail like on the terminal screen when everything froze up and you dragged the mouse across and it made a big mouse trail behind it. She walked forward until she could see Anita's face, but Anita was melting like the time she'd put a little green soldier in a microwave and watched it collapse into a puddle and begin to burn vicious, noxious smoke. Her pointy nose was drooping and her blue eyes were glassy and dull and started leaking out of her face. Her mouth stayed in the same place, but her lips were slugs and her teeth had gone shiny and reflective, a chrome finish.

"I'm dead," Hermione said, and suddenly there were hornets everywhere, stinging and biting her flesh, tearing it off in chunks and carrying it away. They were laughing.

"No," said Anita's slug-lips. "I'm dead. I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead I'm dead

#######

ELKNIWT'S ASTRONOMY SUPPLIES, 1511 NOGAID ALLEY, LONDON

Cymeglen's trunk had been filled with other trunks. This was surprising because according to just about everyone else, the room was filled with old furniture. Ozland asked many times just to be sure, and then had to defend himself from allegations of trunk-madness, whatever that was.

After having afternoon tea, they puddlejumped to the faded exterior of Elkniwt's Astronomy Supplies on 1511 Nogaid Alley. A tattered poster was stuck to the door, reading 'CLEARANCE SALE', then below in smaller letters 'IT'S ALL FREE' and then in even smaller letters 'you bastards'.

They walked in, and found that the owner had apparently gone to a great effort to make the store look thematically appropriate by removing all the lighting fixtures and leaving the entire store in total darkness.

"So," said Ozland, "why's it called Nogaid Alley?"

"Alright," said George, "allow me to set the scene. February 5, 1981. An enterprising Muggleborn salesman by the name of –"

"It's another universe someone busted a hole into," interrupted Ron, tersely.

"– William Dowpill wants to set up a crumpet-stand, but he doesn't have a license."

"Ooh," Fred oohed. "And Ron, every interruption is another candied spider."

Ron shrank back.

"So what does he do? He casts a land-expansion ritual near the edge of Diagon's dimensional pocket, opens up our dimension to blankspace, and sets up his crumpet-stand in it, operating on the, may I say, ironclad logic that the Ministry has no jurisdiction over blankspace, since it technically doesn't exist."

"And what happened next?" asked Fred, hushed.

George gestured expansively with his arms. "The crumpet-stand . . . acted as a seed – hold on, no, a key – a key that opened a door into another universe in the apartment below. But, now here's the thing – the version of William Dowpill in that sideways-universe also casted a land-expansion ritual, and so did the other one the next universe over. Infinitely."

"The strangest thing!" exclaimed Fred.

"And eight universes down . . . there was a universe where pointy hats were considered a form of sexual deviancy, so the Ministry of Magic for that universe sealed itself off, ending the chain. Fifty thousand witches and wizards, all stranded sideways through hyperspace, their own dimensional pockets sealed off from the outside world and glued together with ours."

"A tragedy!"

"So we fined them for four hundred years of unpaid taxes, copyright violations, and construction without permits, and backed it up with the Cup of Magic. Oh, and we put a Jinx on all of them to give them funny accents."

"And that," ended Fred, "is how Nogaid Alley got its name."

Ginny clapped sarcastically.

"Um, I imagine they wouldn't be too happy about any of that. Being debt peons."

"Doesn't matter," said Ron, "they're not real, anyway."

Everyone except for Ozland nodded.

"Um," said Ozland, making a resolution to start sentences with 'um' less, "I might be missing something obvious here, but why is that exactly?"

Ron looked at him as if he'd not only grown another head, but as if that additional head had grown tiny bat wings and begun lifting him up into the air. "Er, they don't have souls, their universes don't have prophecies – and that means they don't have free will –"

"How do you know they don't have souls?"

"'Cos you can't sacrifice their souls in rituals. You can sacrifice their life-force, but there's nothing else to sacrifice. First thing the Ministry tried when we opened up a Gateway."

"Okay, now what about the prophecies and the free will thing?"

Ron sniffed. "Well it's obvious, innit? They don't have any prophecies so they don't have free will."

"A prophecy as in . . . a prediction about the future that has to come true?"

Ron nodded, taking on a more serious tone, as if he was giving an answer for an exam. "Prophecies are the motor-force of history – without prophecies, the only reason why things would happen is because other things happened before them, with all of those things happening as material interactions. But since those material interactions converge on a particular outcome in accordance with prophecy, that implies that free will exists to guide those material interactions towards that outcome. Therefore, sideways-people are biological automatons."

"That's twisty and makes no sense," Ozland wanted to say, and then realised that he'd actually said it.

A shrug from Ron. "Got me a EE in the Land Expansion course, so it can't be all wrong."

"That's the kind of thing I'd make up if I wanted to justify the . . . sideways-peoples' position as eternal debt-peons."

"That's just how it is," shrugged Fred, seeming unconcerned, "might as well not feel bad about it all. Be happy, feel good, and be feel happy-good, that's my life philosophy."

"Where's Mum?" said Ron, knotting his eyebrows.

"She found a cube-shaped globe of the Earth and she's flipping it for a Galleon in the universe with the weird numbers," said Ginny. "At least that's what she said. I'm pretty sure she was lying, since we don't need to flip things anymore."

"On that note," said Fred, "or at least one of those notes – whatever one is closest to what I'm about to talk about – the owner probably put a bunch of cool Curses on his merch, and we're going to need to investigate for investigatory purposes. Ginny, stay at the front – otherwise you'll get lost or have your fingers bitten off by Cursed doorknobs, or both, hopefully."

"I wouldn't – even if I wanted to, which I don't. Gwynne's talking to me over the windspraek."

"Look, Ginny – you don't have to invent imaginary friends to impress us."

"You . . . you two literally met her last year at the Slug Party, what the fuck."

"Yes, Ginny," Fred said, affecting a sympathetic tone, "we definitely met her," he elbowed George, "didn't we, George?"

"Yeah," said George, "shook hands and everything. She was definitely, you know, physically there."

Ginny stormed off.

"Alright, back here in fifteen? Catch you later, Ozzy, Ronniekins."

There was a stretch of silence, during which they walked by a long row of telescopes, all jammed into a brick wall.

"What do you ween that's for?"

"Let's take a look-see," Ozland said, tripping on an uneven bit of carpet.

Ron grabbed his shoulder. "Yeah, mate – not a good idea. You don't just take a look-see through a telescope in the back of a forgotten store abandoned by the dimensional-twin of a mad store-owner . . . oh Merlin, I think I've seen this in a play or something." He held up a finger. "It's on the tip of my tongue."

Ozland waited patiently for over a minute.

"Jungles of Aphrodite," Ron triumphantly burst out. "They look through the telescope, and before they know it, they get sucked in and get put on Venus."

"What then?"

"I fell asleep after that, but the twins said everyone died. I think the main lesson is, don't go looking into random telescopes until you know for sure that they're not Cursed or haven't had eldritch magic done on them." Ron did a twirly-loopy thing with his wand (Ozland wondered whether wand-motions had any pattern or structure) before pointing at the telescopes and ending it with "Revelare maledicta."

Nothing happened.

Ron scratched his head. "You know what would really be useful? If they started glowing bright green. Then I'd be able to tell the difference between 'not cursed' and 'I messed up the spell'. Good work, there, Infectus, you bloody brilliant spellcrafter," he sighed. "Alright, now for the, er, eldritch magic detection spell. Verdobrillo."

The telescopes began glowing bright green.

Ozland stared. "Eldritch or not-eldritch?"

" . . . I don't really know the spell for detecting eldritch magic, that was just the spell for making things glow bright green," Ron admitted. "I'm sorry, I needed a win."

"Silencio," came a soft voice from behind them. A yellowish ray of light struck Ron, who had begun to dodge. Unfortunately, the direction he dodged in was upwards. Ozland swung around as Ron began vigorously mouthing words for some reason, only to see a blonde girl about a half-head shorter than him wrapped in a knitted quilt.

"Are you from the outside?" she asked, very normally.

"From the what?" Ozland reached for his wand, but realised he didn't know anything except for the spell the twins had cast back in the Supermarket except that it was useless for defending himself and he'd forgotten it, and eventually he awkwardly slung his hand by his side.

The girl turned her head, seeming to peer into the gloom.

The quiet stretched on until it was almost unbearable, and then –

"I have wandered here for so many years. I was born in the darkness, my mother was born in the darkness, and her mother before her. But that is long ago," she waved her hand contemptuously, "and I have taken many forms since then. Where do you hail from, stranger?"

Ron began screwing up his eyebrows and pointing his wand at himself.

"Um," Ozland began, instantly hating himself, "um –"

"Ah, a traveller from the city of Um. I had thought it to be long gone, even in my time, but evidently Um has risen once more, as it was foretold by Prachit the Terrible –"

Ron doubled over, gasping. "This is Luna Lovegood and she's in the year below us and she does this all the time and you can't just pretend to be insane whenever Flitwick tries to give you detention the only place where that works is Muggle television –"

"Um," said Ozland, astutely.

"– and why did you silence me?"

"Because," Luna remarked, "I knew you'd ruin my sketch."

"– and how didn't we see you?"

"Something something Nargles."

"What?"

"Ignore him," she said to Ozland, gesturing at Ron, who was rubbing his head. "I'm Professor Lovegood, senior Transfiguration lecturer at Hogwarts and undercover Auror at the DMLE's Bad Things Division. I adopted this youthful form earlier this year to get on the inside of a daffodil-smuggling ring – daffodils are legal, but we have a strict no-ring policy at Hogwarts."

"I'm Ozland Cunningham, Mars-Minister of General Affairs of the New Zealand branch of the Celestian Unorthodox Church," said Ozland automatically. God I'm so confused.

Ron spluttered. "Luna is fourteen or something and I've seen her do this bit three times before. Also, Ozland, what?"

The girl in the quilt tapped her cheek. "I think I might've seen your name somewhere in the Muggle newspapers my dad reads."

...

"Ah, that's it."

"What's it?"

"Exposition. And this late in the story too, how lazy."

"Er," said Ron, "you know we can't see exposition, right, Luna?"

"This is getting too meta for me," muttered Ozland.

"Oh, no," said Luna, breaking into an unusually deep belly-laugh, "this is just my 'pretending we're all in a book' gimmick."

Ozland clasped the side of his head, suddenly overcome by a nauseating wave of unreality. "Look, Ron – let's just pull the telescopes out of the wall and get going. Luna, whatever you were doing . . . what were you doing?"

"Mhm," hummed Luna, completely ignoring the question, "well, you'd want the second and third ones then."

"Come on," said Ron, also clasping the side of his head and looking upwards at the ceiling for no discernible reason, "tell us what all of them do. There's a good gag here, I can sense it."

"I don't think the universe works like that, Ron," said Ozland.

"Well," replied Luna, "the first one shows you the back of your head."

Ron nodded. "Uh-huh."

"Does Luna always make things this weird?"

"The second one shows you the world from five minutes ago."

Ron nodded with more vigour. "Yup, keep going."

"How does she know any of this, anyway? I think she's just making it up."

"The third one shows you what the world would look like if telescopes hadn't been invented, but it's pretty pointless because it's pointing at Sagittarius right now."

"Oh."

"Okay, great! Now that we've wrapped everything up –"

"Oh, and the fourth one sucks you up and puts you on Venus."

#######

It was five o'clock, and Ozland had been awake for twenty-five hours. The twins had bought him a lemonade-flavoured Wakefulness Potion in a crystal vial, which he'd gulped down with wild abandon. The feeling was identical to agrypnomorphine – a dirty, giddy, paranoid buzz. The thought occurred to him: what if agrypnomorphine was Wakefulness Potion? Wakefulness Potion, perhaps adulterated with some other stimulant, manufactured in magical Britain, sold onto the Triad, and concentrated into the powder that businessmen sprinkled onto their coffees and rubbed into their gums?

The sights and sounds around him, dulled by sleep deprivation, became jabbing pains.

He became painfully aware of his own powerlessness.

Ginny was a year younger than him, but knew three years worth of spells.

Ron seemed friendly, if not slightly insecure, but when they'd gone for lunch at Florean Fortescue's, he'd played Ozland for ten one-minute quick games of chess, always starting with the Bongcloud Attack, and had swiftly won each game.

The twins had a Secret Box, a flying carpet, Time Turners and God knew what else, were coming into their Seventh Year, and had invented at least five original Charms.

Mrs Weasley seemed familiar with ritual theory, had three decades of post-Hogwarts experience in magic, and had fought in a war.

Every person passing by, perhaps with the exception of small children, could easily kill him – and the only thing keeping him safe was that, at the moment, nobody had a sufficiently good reason to.

"Come on now, it doesn't take that long."

"Mum, he's on Wakefulness Potion," said Ginny. "And besides, he doesn't have a Ministry-issued floppy disk yet, so he can't do it anyway."

They were on Side-Alley 5K. Or were they? Ozland saw the sign a few minutes ago, but he could easily have been False Memory-Charmed. All he knew was that people who looked like Mrs Weasley, Ginny, and him were standing outside a series of what he assumed were golden fridges, or telephone booths. Was he even him?

"And?"

"And he's obviously in a paranoia loop. Just look at his eyes."

"Oh dear, he is, isn't he? Disconfundo."

Ozland suddenly lost track of what he was thinking about.

"Ozland?" Mrs Weasley said softly.

"Yes?" There was something he was thinking about but he wasn't thinking about it anymore. What had he been thinking about? Think, think, think. He could see the shape of the thought, like a wrapped gift, but he couldn't untie the bow.

"This is a Rejuvenation Booth."

"What?"

"This is a Rejuvenation Booth," Mrs Weasley patiently repeated. "You're going to have to learn how to use one of these, so pay attention. Wand out."

Ozland dug through his pockets for his wand, while Mrs Weasley looked on, disapprovingly. He was struck by the oddity of the scene. The sky now had a purplish tint and the second red moon had the malevolent radiance of a stop-light. The clouds were even odder than when he'd first jumped out of a puddle and into Diagon Alley: spinning triangles, like hookah-rings blown by a god trying to show off. The buildings around them were much posher, with jutting decks and silver rails, but were still intimidating in the same way that forests with tall trees were.

"We'll have to get you a proper holster, too. Now, listen closely. It's very simple. First, do a rotated sigma-swish – by that I mean trace the letter 'M' – then draw a small circle."

He traced out the motions. The sequence felt oddly natural.

"Now, you don't have to do this part." She swished her wand about. "Epísimo aítima pros to Ypourgeío. I, Molly Weasley, request the use of twenty kilothaums for the purpose of a standard rejuvenation ritual to be conducted within Booth Number 1092."

"REQUEST APPROVED," boomed a voice from no particular direction. "THREE KNUTS HAS BEEN CHARGED TO YOUR ACCOUNT."

Mrs Weasley grasped at the air and pulled, until a fragment of a line, thinner than a hair, but thicker than spider silk, appeared between her thumb and index finger. She went around to the side of the booth, where a copper rod jutted out from its scratched surface, and wound the thread around the rod.

The front of the booth opened with a click, revealing a slot, into which Mrs Weasley placed a 3½ inch floppy-disk labelled 'MW, subt-aged, 20s' in neat cursive. Inside the booth, on the ground, was the chalk outline of a circle. She then brought out a needle and pricked her thumb, allowing a drop of blood to spill into the centre, walking into the circle. The door closed.

There was a murmuring of words, a kettle-like squeal, and a loud bang.

Ginny leant against a pole, staring disinterestedly up at the sky.

Mrs Weasley stepped out, looking subtly older. Her eyes were more crinkled, her posture sharper, and there were streaks of gray in her imperceptibly-thinner hair. In his heightened state of awareness, Ozland noticed she was wearing a plain silver wristband, and remembered that Professor McGonagall had been wearing one too – Dumbledore's had been gold. (The thought occurred to him that in a society where everyone looked to be in their mid-20s, status symbols would become necessary.)

"Class of 1966 Gryffindor gala," she said, as if that explained anything. "Have you thought about what House you'll be in?"

"House? Um, not really."

She opened her mouth, as if she was about to say something, when a raven Patronus appeared, perching on top of the booth.

A high-pitched voice rang out from its beak: "Molly, where are you? Albus wants the boy at Hogwarts!"

"Side-Alley 5K, near the booths," Mrs Weasley enunciated crisply. "Professor Flitwick, he teaches Charms and Ritual Theory," she added, after the raven had flown off. "In any case, you should consider Gryffindor. It's the House we were Sorted into, along with Minerva, Chief Warlock Dumbledore – and most of the Light side of the War."

Ozland's head spun with all of the implied capital letters. "Why not the others?"

Ginny, who had been quiet up until that point, piped up. "Slytherins are slimy aristocrats, Hufflepuffs are losers, and Ravenclaws are goody-goody book–"

Mrs Weasley shot Ginny a disapproving look.

A tiny man in green robes whirled into existence on the cobblestones a few feet from them. He slipped on a puddle, almost falling flat on his back before he somehow managed to right himself. "Ah," he squeaked brightly, "Molly, Ginny . . . and you must be Ozland Dwimmersmith, yes?"

"Yes," said Ozland, stiffly, unsure as to what else he should say.

"Then I'm afraid you will have to bid the lovely Weasleys adieu and bring your no-doubt exciting shopping excursion to a close – the Headmaster requests your presence in his office to discuss your lodging situation," the tiny man frowned, "and a few other things, I would imagine."

Ozland shook Mrs Weasley's hand, and after some heavy-handed prompting, Ginny shook his hand too, seeming delighted to almost squeeze it into a pulp. "Thank you," Ozland said with as much genuineness as he could muster, "and I'm not saying that as a nicety either. Today has been – well, I checked to make sure I wasn't dreaming nine times today, that should give you an idea. And I'm still confused about a lot of things, including how your economy works and what the whole dimensional pocket business is about – but all of you are such wonderful people and I don't think there could've been a better family in wizarding Britain to reacquaint me with this world, and I hope one day I can discharge my enormous debt to all of you. Please give Ron and the twins my regards – and as soon as I find out how thermoses work, I'll send a letter to Mr Weasley. Also keep the chocolate safe."

Professor Flitwick took out a checkered handkerchief twice the width of his face, dabbed his eyes, and sneezed into it, very emotionally. "Truly, truly heartwarming. And dear me, would you look at the time – we have about fifteen minutes until you're expected to meet with the Headmaster – we'd better Apparate." He held out his arm. "Irish jig position, please, Ozland."

After a few more goodbyes, they hooked their arms together.

"Three, two, one."

The streets around him vanished and everything went dark and cramped. Ozland remembered Professor McGonagall had said that Apparition felt like being forced through a curly drinking-straw – it turned out to be a very accurate description.

They landed inside a treehouse, spinning on the spot.

He looked around. "How many students does Hogwarts have?"

Flitwick opened the door to the treehouse, revealing a long cable to which a little wooden carriage was attached, a cable that descended from the treetops to a castle obscured by a light mist in the distance. "Hogwarts proper is warded against Apparition – this is an outpost." He opened a second, creaky door which lead into the carriage and hopped inside, seating himself on a patterned stool. "Oh, don't be alarmed – it's Charmed for balance and flawless function," he said, at Ozland's reluctance.

Ozland clambered his way in, tripping on an uneven bit of carpet before finding himself a stool to sit on.

The little man flicked his wand, and the carriage lurched. Looking out the window, he could have sworn the trees were bending out of the way to accommodate its breakneck speed.

"So," said Flitwick conversationally, "had a hectic day, did you?"

"To say the least."

They sat in silence, the professor tapping his knee with frenetic regularity. Despite his jovial disposition, Ozland had the sense that something was making him uneasy.

Flitwick cleared his throat. "Have you thought about what House you'll be in?"

Ozland wondered, not for the first time, whether he had any choice in the matter. From what he'd heard, whatever sorting mechanism Hogwarts was using, it was based around literary archetypes and high-school sitcom clichés, rather than anything sensible. Would it be a hundred-question personality test? Some sort of trial by fire? A mind-reading device? Clearly personal preferences had some effect on the sorting process, otherwise nobody would be attempting to sway him to their way of thinking.

"Er, no."

The Charms Professor seemed to take this as his cue. "Now, I know the Weasleys have probably already sold you on Gryffindor, but," he held up a finger, "Ravenclaw is really where you'll want to be if your temperament is more quiet and studious – we're one of the best-performing Houses academically, and we have very active study and support groups managed by our helpful Prefects – which could be a boon in your case, since you'll be catching up with four years of coursework – and I have to say, our common room has a simply breathtaking vista in addition to our own library –"

"Anything wrong with the other Houses?" Ozland asked.

"– ah, there's nothing wrong with the other Houses per se," Flitwick said, slightly thrown by the sudden interjection – and then, as if considering the question more deeply, he went on. "In Gryffindor, it's almost inevitable you'll become caught up in some wild shenanigans, docked points for something you weren't responsible for – if you're with the wrong people at the wrong time – and Gryffindors . . . tend to be, ah, headstrong, very prone to quick judgement rather than rigorous analysis – make of that what you will," he paused, grimacing, "Slytherin . . . I would recommend strongly against Slytherin." He seemed pained. "If you are Sorted into Slytherin, I would urge you to file an appeal with the Headmaster."

"Why?"

"You haven't been to wizarding Britain in a number of years, is that right?"

"The last time I was here, I was a toddler."

"Mhm," hummed Professor Flitwick, "there is a cultural jump from Muggle to wizarding society, I'm told. But the jump from Muggle to Slytherin society is much greater. Hierarchies, alliances, codes, conspiracies, historical feuds between families, deference, blood purity," he looked particularly disgusted at the word, "Slytherin children are accustomed to all of those things. A wrong word at the House table could have you shunned for the remainder of your years at Hogwarts – very unpleasant, unfortunately I have been witness to the phenomenon a number of times. And, naturally, the Slytherins will assume that you will be a Muggleborn, from whom they demand submissiveness. A momentary lack of civility will be treated as the upending of a natural order, and Slytherins do not take to threats, however slight, to their aristocratic privilege very kindly."

That sounds fairly interesting, actually. "And Hufflepuff?"

Professor Flitwick lightly coughed. "Slytherin is known for its cunning, Ravenclaw for its wit, Gryffindor for its bravery. Hufflepuff is known as the House to which students who possess none of those virtues are Sorted. Although, in all respects, Hufflepuff is a very pleasant, very lovely House to be in, I'm told," he added, unconvincingly.

What is up with these people and constantly shitting on Hufflepuff? "Ravenclaw does sound very appealing."

"Good to hear," Flitwick replied, although he still seemed tense. There was a long lull, in which nothing but the swishing of the trees around them could be heard. The castle loomed larger, and Ozland was able to see parapets and gargoyles and towers jutting out of a medieval edifice. Coming out of a particular tower in the castle was a fork of what looked like frozen lightning. It looked almost like a wound in the air.

"What's that?" Ozland said, pointing.

"What?"

Ozland pointed more accurately.

"Oh, that."

"Yes, that."

"That's nothing to worry about."

"I'm sure, but I'd like to know what it is, if it isn't any trouble."

"It's, ah, an aurora borealis. We get them in Hogwarts, sometimes."

"During the daytime?"

"Yes."

"Just near one of the castle's towers?"

"Yes. They can be highly localised."

"Huh."

"It's none of my business, really," Flitwick said, after some time had passed, his eyes flitting back and forth from one window to another, "but would it be alright if I asked you what area your accidental magic ended up specialising in? It's purely out of personal interest."

"What do you mean?"

"Well, Penelope Clearwater – she graduated last year – can Silence the area around her. Althea Golledge can tell how long any given thing would take or last – she's in the Department of Mysteries, now, works in project management – although, chronomantic abilities are rather rare. It's fairly common with Muggleborns, or in your case, wizardborns who grew up in Muggle society – it usually develops in children after the age of eleven unless they go to Hogwarts, which acts as a magical outlet I suppose you could say."

"I didn't specialise in anything. Unless there's a common theme to levitating pencils and turning water into orange juice –"

The carriage jolted, passing through an open window in the castle, and screeching as it flew through rows of corridors lined with knights and paintings.

"– is this safe?"

"I enchanted it myself," Flitwick said, sounding slightly hurt.

Ozland looked through the front window.

"There isn't any cable in front of us."

"It makes new cable once it runs out," the professor replied, as if that was anywhere near a reassuring explanation.

The carriage stopped outside an enormous, ugly stone griffin, guarding a spiral staircase.

"The staircase stopped working since the man from the Office of Impossibility said it was impossible, so just walk right on up," Flitwick said, tipping his pointed hat. "Cheerio, Ozland – good talking to you."

Ozland waved half-heartedly and paused in front of the gargoyle. After pacing back and forth in front of it, he realised he might as well try, since Flitwick's carriage had zoomed down the halls and nobody else was around. "I'm here to see Dumbledore," he said finally.

The griffin shuffled aside. Ozland began walking up the staircase, stopping at a towering door that visibly glistened and crackled with magic.

A painting of a pompous-looking, tiny-nosed man was fixed to the front. "Here to see Dumbledore?" it asked.

Ozland froze. "Are you . . . conscious?"

"No, I just have an infinite book tucked under my arm that tells me what to say given arbitrary input sentences from random strangers who come up to Dumbledore's door. Of course I'm conscious, you twat. Now, are you here to see Dumbledore or not?"

"I'm at Dumbledore's door, what do you think?"

"What do I think?" scoffed the painting, clearly affronted. "What do I think? Clearly nothing, since my pitiful, illegitimate consciousness is smeared across a three-hundred-year-old canvas and mixed with egg whites. Go in, you bigoted clod – it's open."

Ozland's first reaction was to threaten to pour acid onto it while it was sleeping (that is, if paintings even slept), but it occurred to him that it would be unwise to say this aloud, no less in front of the door to the Headmaster of the school he would be attending –

Will I, though?

To do anything else seemed to run against the logic of the universe. He'd gotten a strange letter from a secret society of wizards inviting him to attend a secret magic school, found out who his real parents were, gone shopping for his supplies . . . saying 'no' after all of that and returning back to his life just didn't seem like an option.

Of course it's an option. Why wouldn't it be an option? Am I going to be ranking available options by narrative convenience now?

It was an option, of course – a narratively-inconvenient option, perhaps, but an option nonetheless. But would he be allowed to choose it? Professor McGonagall had mentioned Memory Charms, the twins had talked at length about magical contracts, Ron had discussed the Imperius – the wizarding world seemed to explode with ways that a much more powerful, senior wizard could mess with his mind in unforeseen ways. And there had been something about a prophecy . . .

George had warned him against going up against Time except on Sundays, and although he'd probably been joking, it was still good advice.

The truth was, he felt a very deep something to the Celestian Unorthodox Church, and that something was like a fish-hook buried deep in his gut, except in a less painful way.

Although, that considered, in the end, hitting the big red nuclear button and ditching the Church for Hogwarts would probably be better for his long-term mental health.

"Internal monologue, eh?" said the painting, still looking rather malicious.

"Yeah."

"Naturally, I don't experience internal monologue, or for that matter, any qualia because I'm just a good-for-nothing p-zombie, post-Classical slab of shi–"

Ozland knocked politely and pushed open the door, which gave way with surprising ease.

Dumbledore's office was what you'd expect of eight centuries of continuous habitation by eccentric old men – and lately, one very eccentric, very old man. The wallpaper was a faded indigo, but it had been unevenly wallpapered over with three other layers of wallpaper and then suffocated by hundreds of paintings of headmasters, most snoring, some talking silently to one another, a few making rude gestures at him. Tables from various eras had made the room their permanent residence, and housed an assortment of things – pointless, intricate little machines that made pointless, intricate sounds. Vellum-bound books cascaded from questionably-stable shelves. There were three doors in the room, one wedged beneath two paintings of pipes, one on the the roof, and one that Ozland's brain insisted was definitely in the room, but, as far as he could see, wasn't anywhere.

At the centre of the chaos was Dumbledore, who was smiling wanly at him with his half-moon glasses, ridiculous beard, and light purple robes – sitting at his desk, on top of which there was an open book with a gun-shaped hole cut into its pages, except the hole was pitch-black, and there was a little stepladder descending into it.

"Ah, Ozland! Don't mind Rudolfus – he's weary of his dreadfully-prolonged, meaningless existence and only attempting to incite students to commit acts of violence against his person in an attempt to break up the tedium. But let it be known, he's very fun once the Butterbeer begins to flow."

"Wouldn't it be more ethical to, you know, end his existence, then?"

"Unfortunately assisted painting-suicide is still outlawed by Ministry decree unless consent is given – otherwise it would be considered murder," said Dumbledore, gravely.

"So if he consents to – "

"The Ministry considers paintings to be non-conscious simulacra, incapable of giving meaningful consent." He threw up his hands. "The world is a mad, mad place, Ozland. But I digress – it is too common an affliction among us youthful old men to stride off the beaten conversational path and into the forests of the night – would you care to take a seat? Ah, the red chesterfield, an excellent choice."

Ozland couldn't help but stare at the book-hole. "Professor Flitwick said something about lodging arrangements?"

"Indeed. Professor Mogpipe who teaches Eighth Year Magical Maintenance, was walking down the third floor corridor not so long ago, considering the issue of your far-awayness from Britain having been prompted by myself, and by fortunate happenstance, found a room which should accommodate you for the five days up to the beginning of the school term." The indecision must have been plain on his face, for Dumbledore frowned. "You have obligations at home. How utterly inconsiderate of me to make such an imposition."

Ozland rubbed his eyes. "No, it's fine. When I first, you know, grasped the whole scope of what was going on, how isolated everything was – I mean, it's literally the other side of the world, I couldn't be further away from New Zealand – I thought I could just, well, I'm not sure, maybe I could rent an apartment or bunk up in one of the Weasleys' spare rooms. I could learn magic at Hogwarts and just have nothing I needed to do." He yawned. The Wakefulness-whatever-it-was was wearing off, apparently. "That sounded really great at first, but then, well, what would I be doing it for? What would I be going to Hogwarts for?"

"To make new friends and devote yourself to the study of the arcane arts?"

He paused. "Well, actually those would be some good reasons to go to Hogwarts. But people need me back home and I can't just disappear one night and never see them again. Besides the fact that it would start a civil war and probably end in a nuclear exchange covering Australasia. But it would still be hard," he waved his hands about helplessly, "knowing all of this exists."

Dumbledore leaned forward. "Perhaps I can make the decision easier for you."

"Go on."

"If you do not attend Hogwarts, you will explode."

Nothing was said for a few seconds and then –

"Literally?"

Dumbledore tilted his glasses. "Literally."

"How? Why?"

"Ozland," the ancient, yet 20s-something-looking wizard boomed, "every time you become truly – and I mean truly – angry, you roll the dice, so to speak. Your magic is untamed, uncontrolled, uncontrollable – unless you receive a formal education, taxing your brains, straining your magic, and draining out your emotions on a regular basis. Have you heard of spontaneous combustion?"

"Yes."

"Need I say more?"

"Shit. Uh, sorry."

"No need to apologise, Ozland," Dumbledore said, "we are all powerful wizards and we are all under fifty-six privacy Charms, so feel free to cuss like a drunken sailor."

" . . . that whole exploding thing really, really did not make it easier to decide, just so you know."

"That should present no issue," said Dumbledore, unsheathing his wand. "Because, of course –"

HE'S GOING TO MEMORY-CHARM YOU, screamed a voice in his head.

Ozland jumped out of the chair, his eyes wide.

" – we can simply cast the Ritual of the Cubic Day. Ozland?" Dumbledore looked puzzled.

He sat back down again, thoroughly ashamed. "I thought you were going to Memory Charm me, or force me into a magical contract, or something."

"Oh," said Dumbledore, looking disappointed, "you have read Skeeter's account of the War, then?"

"What?"

Dumbledore flicked his wand, and a book whipped out from the shelf and into his hand. "Rita Skeeter wrote this . . . dramatised account of the War. Most of it was received in poor taste, but I'm told it leaves the reader with an impression of me as a manipulative, condescending, doddering old man who has a rather derivative fondness for Memory Charms."

"I haven't read it. Why don't you just have her killed if it's such an issue?"

"Come again?"

"Or frame her for something and get her locked up."

The Chief Warlock seemed disturbed by the idea. "Is that standard political practice in New Zealand?"

That there was any other form of political practice for dissidents hadn't occurred to him. "Ye-es."

"Ozland," Dumbledore drummed his fingers on the wooden surface of the table, "I am not the kind to so lightly commit an act as vile as murder, nor to condemn a woman, innocent of all crimes, but the non-crime of offending the critical sensibilities of a powerful man, to the Dementors of Azkaban. But that aside, were Lucius to, on hearing the news of Rita Skeeter's demise, realise that the informal rules of proper conduct had been fundamentally altered – that every journalist who penned an unflattering article, every writer with an inflammatory passage, every author whose depiction of his character was to him unbecoming, was game – would he not respond in kind with the means at his disposal, extenuating the bloodshed beyond my original intentions, were they murderous? Or perhaps, it is the press that you ought to imagine – one of their own kind locked away, a woman who knew no boundaries when it came to levying criticism at the wealthy and ennobled, to airing secrets, whether real or imagined, to the British public? Would they hesitate for a second longer before unveiling corruption and bringing the guilty, those untouchable by the courts, to justice? Would they, in their minds contemplating the Dementors, shelve criticism and put a halt to affronting the well-connected?"

"Good point," Ozland conceded. If he came up with that on the spot, that was impressive. "Um, I think we've wandered off-topic."

Dumbledore brought out a notebook and flipped through it. "I make sure to dispense at least three pieces of wisdom with every conversation. Ah, yes. The Ritual of the Cubic Day will, in the words of its inventor, split your mind-essence across the two faces of the Time Cube, allowing you to experience two days for each day that passes in two different countries. It is very rarely conducted."

"Because it doesn't make any sense?"

"Because the ritual is rather messily structured and my colleagues in the Cyprian Institute believe that it could be simplified along Modernist lines. Eugenray was a devout adherent to the Multimodalist school of ritual theory, which has since come out of fashion."

"Wouldn't it also create . . . internal consistency issues?" asked Ozland, skeptically. "You know, all of the usual guff with time travel. Say I wake up in New Zealand, hear on the news a bomb went off in the Underground, go to sleep, wake up in Britain which is, what, twelve hours behind – you know what I mean?"

Dumbledore nodded. "Internal consistency issues, as a general principle, can be avoided by minimising forward-backward information flow, as the chronomancers call it. Hogwarts, I would think, would be sufficiently informationally-insulated from New Zealand, hence why the ritual came to mind."

"So what's the catch?"

"A sleepless night would be a paradox, which could only be resolved through your death. However, that possibility can be prevented through familiarity with sleeping Charms, or with a specialised device, which, should you choose to perform the ritual, Professor Snape will obtain for you. The ritual also demands the fingernail from the thumb of your left-hand."

"That's it?"

"Indeed."

"Okay, let's do this."

"Excellent. First, we will have to find our way to the International Date Line over the Pacific Ocean."

"Great, what wacky mode of transportation are we going to use this – "

Dumbledore snapped his fingers, and they were suddenly hovering over the ocean under a night sky.

Ozland panicked, seeing the waves crashing beneath him. He tapped his foot, feeling an invisible surface below him that kept him from falling into the water. Wind rushed through his hair. "I'll be able to do that finger-snapping teleportation thing one day, right?"

Dumbledore laughed loudly, seeming to find his question uproariously funny, before becoming serious. "The Ritual of the Cubic Day," he said, "transports your mind-essence to your golem body in the instant following its completion – in your case, to New Zealand a few hours from now – so before we begin, there are things you must know sooner than later."

"I'm listening."

"The agenda for tomorrow. Or, from your perspective, yesterday. First, Professor Trelawney will assess your career options. Second, there will be the customary meeting with the other new non-First-Year students. That is all."

"Okay, noted."

"Now, this ritual is very clever, is filled with subtle references to many different works of fiction, contains three koans in Pig Latin, and is also a palindrome, so it would be advisable for you to listen very carefully to appreciate it fully."

#######

Luna's exposition

London Evening Herald

"WORST GANG VIOLENCE IN TWENTY YEARS":

DEATH-COUNT IN NEW ZEALAND "HOLY WAR" REACHES 1,380

[...] called a "blessed child" by the self-declared St. Matchwell, Cunningham was not available to comment [...]

The Observatory

OPINION: INTERVENTION IS NEEDED IN NZ

[...] the New Zealand branch of the Celestian Unorthodox Church has been described variously as a cult, a government, a gang, a criminal syndicate, a political party, and a private militia [...] supported by a patchwork alliance – Tip Top Ice Cream Ltd., Four Star Hotels, and the Nisango – and, our source says, is largely controlled by Rushabh (Jupiter-Minister of the New Zealand branch of the C.U.C), a warlord who threatened to detonate a nuclear device to ascend to power, Ozland Cunningham (Mars-Minister of General Affairs), an unknown who entered the upper echelons of the C.U.C after the 1991 Holy War, Evelyn Rawter (Mars-Minister of Propaganda and Public Relations), the daughter of St. Matchwell who is in formal command of the New Zealand branch of the C.U.C, and Donovan Yu (Mars-Minister of Justice & Defense), the alienated son of Four Star Hotels' CEO and the commander of FSH's militia in the region.

#######

26 AUGUST – INCORPORATED TERRITORY OF THE CELESTIAN UNORTHODOX CHURCH, AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

Ozland woke up on his couch to someone banging on the door. And he woke up, and it was all a dream, he thought. And wow, that was an amazingly cleverly-written ritual.

The banging persisted, rattling windows.

"Jesus, I'm coming!" he shouted.

He reached the door in a record five seconds and swung it wide open.

It was Evelyn, standing there with the bright blue dress and flowery hat she used for formal occasions. Ozland thought it made her look like a visiting royal, which was probably the intended effect. "Where the fuck have you been and why haven't you responded my – wow, you look awful."

"Well I'm sorry, Ev, but having one of my best mates suddenly suicide on me made me want a night to myself with a couple of beers," he said, feeling immensely guilty at the lie.

"Well I'm sorry, Oz, since I've been trying to fucking reach you for the last five hours to tell you someone leaked Rushabh's suicide to the press before we could set up the official story and that, in accordance with time-honoured tradition, his fucking Unsealing Ceremony, you know, the one where they read out his successor for the position of Jupiter-Minister of the whole of New Zealand, is happening in Gordon Coates in twenty minutes and we're on the fucking guest-list."

"Oh," said Ozland.

"Yes," said Evelyn. "I thought you might say something like that."

#######

19 HAMPSTEAD ROAD, HAMPSTEAD GARDEN SUBURB, HEATHGATE, LONDON – OCTOBER 2, 1991 – ABOUT FOUR YEARS AGO

One thousand soldiers face an advancing mob, resolute.

A bottle spirals, turns three times, and shatters.

In a second, gunfire fills the air.

Blood spills out in litres, and someone screams a –

Hermione had faked a cold. She'd never done it before, so she'd gotten away with it. She was a pattern, and her parents were patterns, and they had a pattern inside them that told them how her pattern was supposed to go, and she had broken the pattern, so she'd gotten away with it. Jessica had come down with a cold, and Hermione remembered the cold-pattern, so when she woke up that morning she reproduced the cold-pattern and her parents reproduced the worried-parent-pattern and checked her temperature and said they would call the doctor and made her a mug of cocoa and told her to lie down, all according to the worried-parent-pattern. By nine o'clock, her parents were gone according to their schedule-pattern, and she began thinking.

She began thinking about Negaloth's pattern, and how she could disrupt it. She began thinking about tall skyscrapers and the economy and people in business-suits running to and fro and –

This isn't healthy, said a little voice in her head.

She responded to that little voice, saying that health was just a pattern but she was different because she controlled her own pattern. Not many people controlled their own patterns and when they did, they were considered unhealthy by normal-patterned people – so there.

May 7 was a pattern. May 7 was a recurring calendar date, and May 7 was a recurring memory. She kept remembering May 7 and remembering it again, but now she controlled her own pattern, so she didn't have to remember it.

She was reading 'The Depression and the Rise of the All-American Oligarchy' when there came a knock on the door. The postman was there, and the postman had a package. The package was for her. She opened up the package with scissor-blades, and inside the package were hundreds of black cassette tapes, all numbered.

Now this was a mystery.

She went up to her room, and put the first cassette into her cassette-player, and put the cassette-player on her nightstand, and listened. At first, there was an anti-hiss of silence, and then there was a low voice. "Hermione," it said, without inflection, so soft, so neutral that it verged on sinister. "Please, listen very closely."

Her palms began to sweat. She had the sudden, nauseating feeling that everything up until that moment had been a mechanical dream. She'd reduced her world to patterns, and forgotten that it was real.

"I am going to talk to you, and you can talk back to me, because I know what you will say. When I say 'end recording', you need to press the stop button. If I tell you not to play the tape for a certain period of time – a day, a week, a month – that's what you need to do. You can only talk after I say 'end recording'. End recording."

She obediently reached forward, pushing the stop button. "Who are you?" she asked aloud, suddenly feeling very vulnerable.

Play. "I'll give you a clue. You watched part of a documentary on me on the BBC yesterday. End recording." Stop.

She rolled a pair of dice on her nightstand. "What did I just do?"

Play. "You tried to test the outer limits of my predictive capabilities by rolling a pair of dice. Two and six. But enough of this, you must know who I am now. Any questions? End recording." Stop.

Hermione bit her lip. "What do you want, Bolshoy?"

Play. "Melodramatic, but pointed," went the voice, as if it were commenting on a half-decent TV drama. "Every thought leaves a subtle dent on the world, Hermione – every significant choice, every unspoken word. I can tell you what Anita was thinking, as the bullets passed through her body. I can tell you what emotions flashed through her brain as she bled to death on the stones of Trafalgar Square. Pain, of course – long, long, pain. But as her lungs exhaled for the last time, a dent was made in the world – the dent of a powerful thought. The powerful thought was her realisation, in her dying moments, that Hermione, her closest friend, had seen her, and that Hermione would avenge her. The future is not certain – even the brightest outlines are blurred, but I know enough to tell you this, Hermione: your vengeance is justified, and moreover, it is right."

The voice slowed. "If you give me the opportunity to help you, I will. I will not take over your project, as it were – it is yours, and yours alone. I can offer you guidance – moral or scientific – connections from Britain and beyond, and resources in abundance. Evidently I have planned in advance, hence the additional cassette tapes. I want you to think today about my offer, and remember this: Negaloth has sacrificed millions at the altar of the temple of profit. To those millions suffering at its leisure, a strike against Negaloth would be a sign that there is justice in the universe, and that they can wield it. There are very few people in Britain who can do what you could do, Hermione, and they are fewer by the day. End recording."

Stop.

"I'd have to be a real dunce not to accept your help, wouldn't I? Count me in."

Play. "Excellent. Now, listen very, very closely."

#######

Chapter 7: The Secret Society Secret Society

A/N: Only one month this time, I think.

#######

Irish Wizarding Gazette

DRAGON ON TOP OF MOUNTAIN ACCUSED OF TAX EVASION

The dragon who lives in the cave on the top of Mt Dweomdale has recently come under fire due to an anonymously-penned letter, purported to have been written by three prominent Ministry taxpeople, who claimed that the dragon has used various shell corporations to cheat the Ministry out of approximately forty thousand Galleons over the past ten years. The dragon, when asked to comment on the allegations, was seemingly insulted and affronted, calling the authors of the letter "the redistributionist knights of yore, reincarnated into bureaucratic busybodies", emphasising its continual investments into local Irish businesses and the magical community as a whole amounting to twenty million gold coins as of today, and its "positive role" as a "stimulator of economic growth".

The dragon made further comments, suggesting that if business conditions became unfavourable, it would "withdraw investment" and "eat everyone".

#######

THE NORTH TOWER, HOGWARTS, SOMEWHERE – 26 AUGUST, 1995

In the Divination classroom, a boy with gray-brown hair and a woman with coke-bottle glasses faced fifty cups of tea, all recently drained.

"Oh dear. This has never happened before."

"What hasn't happened before?"

"The Chudley Cannons will win 60-2 against the Wigtown Wanderers in the Quidditch Northwestern Regional Semi-Finals. It's a shame I'm banned from all of the betting clubs," she remarked, with a hint of wistfulness.

"What about my future career?"

"Oh, I suppose you could interpret it that way, too," Professor Trelawney coughed. She tapped her wand to a sheet of parchment, and the tea pattern quickly inked itself in, dot by dot. "Take this tea-pattern to the Ministry Office of Statistics, they'll process it," she said, handing it to him.

"And what am I . . . how am I supposed to get there?"

"Puddlejumping, but – oh, the caretakers will have fixed the leaky fountain by now, you'd better use the Hedge."

"The Hedge?" Evidently Professor Trelawney wasn't as perceptive as she'd appeared, or she was leaving implicit unanswered questions in all of her answers as some sort of incomprehensible game.

"You'll find it in the gardens that you saw when you came in with Professor Flitwick."

" . . . I had a fair bit of trouble with finding breakfast so I doubt I'll be able to make my way outside without directions."

The Divination Professor seemed to lose interest, turning back to her study of the tea leaves. "Just turn eight lefts, that usually does it."

Ozland turned to leave, stumbled over an uneven bit of carpet, and then turned back. "Hold on, I forgot to ask – er, no, I asked but I don't think I got the answer I was looking for – "

"An accident from a few years ago when Lord Riddley – the Rituals and DADA Professor at the time – covered for Pomona for a Seventh Year Herbology class."

"No, look, I'll be more clear – "

"Lean back against it while whispering 'Ministry Office of Statistics Core', but make sure to say 'Core', or else it might take you to one of the non-Core universes on the Registrar and you'll living the rest of your life in a lower reality without realising it. It's happened before," she added, shrugging.

After turning eight lefts and crossing a drawbridge that didn't go over anything so far as he could tell, he wandered through the garden (which was quite lovely) and came to the Hedge. Ozland hadn't encountered many menacing hedges in his life, but this was certainly one of them. It stood twenty feet high, and the leaves were sharp as an overused simile. They weren't dark leaves either – not dark at all, but an infinitely more dangerous-looking shade of milky green.

All in all, it was the sort of hedge you'd expect to see growing around the home of a one-eyed man who nobody had ever seen except briefly as a window silhouette during a lightning storm after accidentally throwing a frisbee into his backyard at night.

Some hedges said things like 'don't lean against me, I have pollen and prickles', while this hedge was quite clearly saying: 'don't lean against me, or else.'

There was something vaguely discomforting about the idea that it could send him to another universe. He'd go back to Hogwarts and everyone would be part-Neanderthal and he probably wouldn't realise anything was wrong until the Core Ministry issued a missing persons notice except that it'd be too late since he'd already had three children and been expelled from Stanford after publishing a doctoral thesis entitled 'A Novel Means of Reversing Cryptographic Transformations of Names of God'.

"Ministry Office of Statistics Core," he murmured, resigned, and leant back into the Hedge, which quite readily gave way. Branches closed around his field of vision. Hogwarts became fragments of architecture, only visible as gaps between the leaves.

##

The time Ozland spent inside the Hedge was an eternity, made all the more disquieting by the constant wriggling and squirming of the branches, shuffling his body to some unseen destination. He had the unshakeable feeling that the Hedge was being tender and careful with him, like child hugging a teddy-bear on the verge of falling apart, or a very big person hugging a very smaller person while trying not to shatter any of their bones. At one point, he heard the distinctive sounds of a motorway and the honking of a horn, and the skeletal branches in the Hedge quickly tugged him upward, after which the motorway sounds became softer and disappeared. It was all mostly dark, except for a few sprinklings of light – white, blue, and sometimes green and orange, which allowed him to see apples attached to some of the branches, but that didn't last for very long before he was squeezed out from a potted plant into a humming, thrumming room.

For the Office of Statistics, it didn't look too busy. The humming, thrumming room was bare save for a bored-looking clerk sitting at a mahogany desk, on top of which perched a little box with hints of cogs and wheels poking out, from which all the humming and thrumming was originating. It was also rather small – a tad larger than a work cubicle – and filled with pipes, all of which fed into the little box.

"How may I help you?" The clerk's nose was buried in a book, and accordingly the words came out as muffled and all jammed together, as if they were a super-word in some language whose vocabulary consisted entirely of perfunctory phrases.

Ozland swallowed and waved about the speckled parchment. "It's a tea-pattern, to do with careers." He stopped, and started again. "Professor Trelawney said I should come here."

Apparently this was enough for the clerk to make sense of, for he took the parchment from Ozland, rolled it up, tied a blue ribbon around it, and fed it into a hole in the machine.

Maybe he was imagining it, but Ozland thought he could hear a whirring sound above the mechanical din, and all of a sudden, the machine spat out a long string of paper. The clerk promptly took the paper, unhooked what looked like a metal plunger from the back of the machine and suckered it to his lips.

"Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33, request for tea-reading interpretation, subsection: career orientation. Message is as follows: Twenty two point five, sixty-three point zero, ninety-eight point two, seven point zero, three point two eight nine, one hundred and nine point three. End." The office-clerk spoke, reading off the paper. Each word had a garbled reverb, as if it was bouncing around between two sheets of scrunched-up aluminium foil.

Soon enough, a crisp female voice came back, coming from every direction, like an airport announcement. "Head of Computation, message to Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33. Reply is as follows, in ranked order: one, prophecy reinterpretation, two, land expansion, three, foreign relations office. End."

"Got that?" the clerk asked, turning back to his book.

"So those are the jobs I've been assigned?"

Eyebrows arched. "Heavens, no. Those are the jobs you'll end up doing."

"Then what's the point of all of this, then?"

"So," the clerk said, slowly, "you can prepare to do them while you're at Hogwarts . . . unless you're an Underperson?"

"No – "

"Oh, good," the clerk visibly relaxed, "some of them figured out how to undo the Foreign Accent Jinx, and killed their counterparts in the Core to take their place. Awful shit. Muggleborn, then?"

"It's rather complicated, but hold up – if I study prophecy reinterpretation at Hogwarts and I wouldn't have studied it otherwise, isn't the, er, tea reading causing what it's supposed to predict in the first place?"

"Well," the office-wizard said, not seeming to give the matter much thought, "everything has to be caused by something."

"Well – "

"So really, if you don't end up working in the Department of Mysteries, then what made the tea-reading say you would work there in the first place? It's a logical contradiction, innit? Can't happen."

At Ozland's thoughtful silence, he went back to his book.

"Er, sorry to trouble you again – but how might I get back to Hogwarts?"

"And how am I supposed to know that?"

"I thought you might, that's all."

The clerk sighed, pulled the metal plunger out again, and placed it to his lips. "Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33, request for information, subsection: general. Message is as follows: how might a pesky Hogwarts student get back to Hogwarts?"

Half a minute passed. "Head of Computation, message to Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33. Reply is as follows: and how am I supposed to know that? End."

"Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33, general reply. Message is as follows: I thought you might, that's all. No worries. End."

"Head of Computation, message to Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33. Reply is as follows: I'll have to ask the Department of Transportation. End."

The tubes were silent for a while, before the same voice piped up again. "Head of Computation, message to Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33. Message is as follows: Department of Transportation wants to know whether the pesky Hogwarts student knows how to ride a dragon, please reply. End."

"Well," said the clerk, "do you?"

"No," Ozland replied patiently, "of course I fucking don't."

"No need to get shirty – "

"I swear to fucking Matchwell, half of the time I spend here is using some nutty way of moving from – "

"Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33, general reply. Reply is as follows: No, he doesn't know how to ride a dragon."

" – one place to another. And how long is this going to take?"

"Shouldn't be too long," the clerk said pleasantly, flipping over to another page. "You know, the Ministry used to do so many pointless, counterproductive, useless things before Minister Tesla's reforms – now, we do them twenty percent faster."

A rumbling came through the tubes, heralding a message. "Head of Computation, message to Office of Statistics, Cubicle 33. Message is as follows: Department of Transportation says 'Go out the door and turn eight lefts.' End."

Ozland held up his finger, open-mouthed, and then went out the door.

###

They had filtered, one by one, into the expansive room in Hogwarts' south-west tower. Was it the room where Peeves threw pineapple cakes at a visiting Soviet delegation in 1956? Hermione wasn't sure, her brain was a little scattered today.

It couldn't help but be scattered, she reminisced – if she'd tried to make sense of the entire magical world at first glance, her brain wouldn't just be scattered; instead, little chunks of it would be landing on Neptune just about now.

For a long time, there was an uncomfortable silence in the circle of Muggleborns, and then a boy walked in, grinning uneasily. Althea Golledge, who, along with Penelope Clearwater, was sitting comfortably in the centre of the circle, cleared her throat – a rather rough, alarming sound. Hermione only knew her and Penelope's names because she'd politely pressed Professor McGonagall for every possible detail beforehand.

"Introductions, I think, would be appropriate. I'm Althea Golledge," she began, flatly. "I work in the Department of Mysteries as a project manager and I can't say any more than that."

"My name is Penelope Clearwater. I graduated last year," Penelope murmured, "desk clerk at the Ministry."

The uneasily-grinning boy introduced himself as Terry Boot, without elaboration.

Kevin Entwhistle just said his name quickly and quietly, his eyes darting about the room, as if waiting for someone to challenge him on the fact.

"Yosif Almazbekov," volunteered someone she couldn't see. "If you're thinking about my name, I just came here a few days ago from Kyrgyzstan. I'm looking forward to studying at Hogwarts and it's good to see my fellow students," he added, softly. Terry stared oddly at him.

"Ozland Cunningham," another boy said, and then paused, as if considering how to construct a particularly delicate sentence. "Both of my parents lived in Britain and were magical, but they died during the War and put me in the care of a Muggle couple in New Zealand. I . . . am involved in paragovernmental affairs."

She wondered what he'd left out. He'd definitely left something out. Nobody paused that long without leaving something out.

Everyone was looking at her now. "Hermione Granger," she said, her throat suddenly dry. "I'm ... well," you'll all get to know me soon enough and I'd prefer not to box myself in by summarising who I am in a handful of words, she wanted to say, but, after swallowing nervously, she finally managed to say: "I'm from Heathgate and I was studying to be a dentist before I got my acceptance letter, but I don't think I'll be doing that now."

Althea chuckled, no one else did.

The last person who'd spoken was on the opposite side of the circle to Hermione and –

As she looked at that last person, three thoughts, in rapid succession, passed through her head.

The first was: isn't he the one who fixed my pneumatic modulator?

The second was: oh, I remember, his name was Harry Evans-Verres.

Her heart skipped a beat.

The third wasn't a thought so much as the surprised 'oh!' of a sudden connection that her brain had made – the connection in this case being that the person who she'd gone to, to get a motorcycle part repaired, also defeated He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named as a baby.

She kept quiet, wondering who else had figured it out.

There was a fourth thought, more of a subconscious voice, reprimanding her for not paying more attention.

"Oh, right," the ender-of-the-Wizarding-War said, almost absently, "Harry, pleased to make your acquaintances – Hermione, Ozland, Yosif, Kevin, Terry, Penelope, Althea." He nodded to everyone as he said their names

"Harry who?" asked Golledge, with a hint of impatience.

"Just Harry."

"Wait, what?"

###

Just Harry.

As he reached the drawbridge, Dumbledore's phoenix-Patronus had told him to go to the third room on the corridor on the third floor near the south-west tower. Ozland had asked, almost sarcastically, whether he should turn eight lefts to get there, and the phoenix had said:

"I see you're getting the hang of it."

And then it winked.

Sitting in that room, it suddenly occurred to Ozland that maybe the Patronus had winked, rather than Dumbledore.

" . . . I'm looking forward to studying at Hogwarts and it's good to see my fellow students."

People were looking at him now. Oh, so they were going counter-clockwise?

"Ozland Cunningham," he said, immediately, and then stopped to think about how he would introduce himself. How had everyone else done it? Maybe, given how often this sort of thing was happening, he would do well to work out some sort of schema and prepare various introductions for different situations. He'd never needed to introduce himself before.

A long pause. "Both of my parents lived in Britain and were magical, but they died during the War and put me in the care of a Muggle couple in New Zealand. I . . . am involved in paragovernmental affairs."

There. He'd paused just long enough to create intrigue.

"Hermione Granger," said a girl, presumably Hermione Granger, who looked about his age – definitely younger than Penelope and Althea. "I'm ... well," she seemed flustered, "I'm from Heathgate and I was studying to be a dentist before I got my acceptance letter, but I don't think I'll be doing that now."

No shit.

"Oh, right," muttered the boy next to him, "Harry, pleased to make your acquaintances – Hermione, Ozland, Yosif, Kevin, Terry, Penelope, Althea."

"Harry who?"

"Just Harry," said the boy.

"Wait, what?"

"Pardon?"

"What do you mean, 'Just Harry'?" said Althea.

"Oh, I see where the confusion is coming from," Harry said, helpfully, "my family name is spelt with silent letters. Only mute Dutch people can hear it."

If this was intended to provoke some further reaction, it failed, for Althea only shook her head. "N'importe quois. You're probably all wondering why we're here today. Unless someone has already figured it out – ?"

"We're all Muggleborns," Hermione said.

"Not all of you," Althea responded readily, "no, all of you are entering into your Fifth Year with no prior knowledge of magic. To call that a disadvantage is a catastrophic understatement. A good half of you," she said, "will fail. No, allow me to amend that – unless you are exceptional, you will fail." She stared around the room, meeting everyone eye-to-eye. "Once you fail, you will be moved back a year. Once you fail that year, you will be moved back another year. There are four successive years for you to fail in, and each year you are moved back into will be more and more embarrassing than the last."

"That is," Penelope continued, "if you don't support each other. If you support each other, you might all be able to scrape a passing grade, and er, avoid getting picked on. I didn't have anyone to support me – I was, ah, I was the only Muggleborn in my year. I had to learn how to defend myself, but, well, defensive magic hasn't ever been my strong suit," she laughed uncertainly, "so I just holed up in the Ravenclaw Library." She seemed to shift in tone, and was deadly serious all of a sudden. "Don't end up in Slytherin. Ideally you want to be in Hufflepuff or with the Gryffindors, Ravenclaw as a third best. Also if you get injured, go to Madam Pomfrey immediately and don't be afraid to mention names. Dumbledore and McGonagall are also good people to go to, but they're both really busy. Just keep your head down and avoid trouble, try and earn House points but don't look like a teacher's pet while you're doing it."

"And if you all end up in different Houses, the most important thing is to stick together," Althea said. "It might sound cliché, it might sound uninspiring, but unless you want to go back to being a goddamned dentist, you're going to have to do it."

There was a collective murmur of agreement. Hermione looked affronted.

"Which brings me to the real reason why the Headmaster keeps organising these little pep-talks – you'll all need to get to know one another. I need a fucking smoke," said Althea abruptly, "ask Penelope if you have any questions."

A long silence ensued.

"It's always hard to start off a conversation organically," said Harry, "so let me try at it, and if I don't succeed, we'll go around clockwise with everyone giving their best conversational prompt: Hermione, do I know you from somewhere?"

###

Hermione, do I know you from somewhere?

The problem was, of course, that he did. Hermione knew full-well that he'd heard her doing an Estuary accent and pretending to be an older motorcyclist on a single night in February, about two years ago.

The second problem was that she hadn't expected him to recognise her. Unless she was overthinking it and Harry had genuinely made a mistake ...

No, it seemed an unlikely sort of question to ask.

Oh damn, if she thought for any longer it would look like –

"I don't think so," she said, furrowing her brow, "I know you from 'Rise and Fall' and 'A Muggleborn Guide', but I don't think we've ever met in person."

Harry closed his eyes and snapped his fingers. Something about the motion made her wary. "I've heard your voice before."

Damn, damn, damn. That was the problem with being clever and mysterious – people tended to remember you. "Oh! Do you listen to the radio?"

"Sometimes," Harry said, neutrally.

"The BBC interviewed our school in year eight," should she go for generalities or specifics? she'd already established that she had a good memory – so probably specifics, "it was about the IRA bombings. I talked about it, and the whole 'candid mainstream-but-insightful political opinion from a little girl' thing probably pulled a few heartstrings and they wrote my parents, asking permission to rebroadcast it a few times."

"That might've been it. Ah," Harry raised his eyebrows, and then lowered them, "I was going to bring up the Republican motorcycle bombings in Sussex from earlier this week, but the IRA doesn't make for lighthearted conversation. Maybe we should move onto something else." His face was blank.

"Quite," Hermione said, her mouth dry. "Ozland?"

"Yes?" He wasn't that loud, she noticed, but his voice carried like a wineglass struck in a crowded dining room.

"Harry suggested that we go around clockwise, each giving our best conversational prompts until something stuck," she explained, desperate to move the conversation as far away as possible from anything related to the 1993 Negaloth Bombings.

"Oh." The boy tapped his index finger on his knee, as if he were discreetly communicating a signal in morse. "What's your superpower, then, Hermione?"

"Pardon?"

"Superpower," Penelope snorted, shaking her head, "unstructured magic, you mean."

"Er," she said, panicking, "it's a power, maybe, not a superpower, though. I can," her voice wasn't stuck in her throat, but little pieces of it were escaping and making weird warbling sounds, "I can make it so people don't notice me. I'm not invisible when I do it, I can still see my reflection in mirrors, but when I do it, it's impossible to notice me." And I don't show up on security footage, either, but that seems like a silly thing to say. For all she knew, she was drugged up in a government black-site where they were interrogating her before breaking apart her psyche and reassembling her into a British super-spy, or a human WMD – or maybe they would just slice up her brain. It was a miracle, really, that it hadn't happened already – if someone was less-than-discreet about their unstructured magic and the Obliviation Squad was too late, well, that person would be screwed, to say the least.

"I can fix things," Harry murmured. "The first time it happened was with my parents' wedding bowl. I wished it unbroken, and the pieces snapped cleanly back together. I genuinely thought I was hallucinating, but I wasn't. Once I'd realised that I could, I did all the usual things – run experiments, try to figure out where the limits were, find applications. You'd think," he sighed, and there was an almost palpable edge of frustration in the sigh, "that there'd be something clever you could do with it. I decided I would find something clever, make millions of pounds, conquer the universe," he looked utterly serious, but then he broke out into a good-natured smile, as if to suggest he'd been joking – of course he'd been joking – who the heck wanted to conquer the universe, anyhow?

He stopped. "My plan, the plan I drew up when I was twelve, was this: I would set up a repair shop, put it in the papers, and every night, I would come up with ten brilliant ideas and try out every single one of them, until I found some unconventional way to use my power that worked, and then I would shut down the shop and go on to more pressing issues, such as solving world hunger and ending poverty by Tuesday. And, well," he shrugged, "what can I say? I'm still running that shop."

"The Repairing Charm?" said Yosif.

"Something deeper than the Repairing Charm, I think. The Repairing Charm returns things to their original states. My power is different. I can fix things into shapes they weren't in originally – ye gods, Penelope, you're not holding out on any more sensible names for it, are you? Power?"

"Apart from unstructured magic?"

"It doesn't work well, does it?" Ozland remarked. "My unstructured magic waxes by the hour. It's like saying benzoylmethylecgonine when you mean coke. What we're really looking for is something proper and sensible-sounding that rolls off your tongue, too."

"It's rubbish," Terry said, clearly wanting to throw in his opinion. "Our magic isn't unstructured at all."

"It's unstructured compared to rituals, wand-magic, runes, divination, and just about every other field of magic," Hermione said.

"Or at least, to whatever Ministry busybody invented the term." Harry frowned. "Probably the brilliant sod who came up with the idea of naming a national exam after a nocturnal bird."

"Dwaemer," said Penelope suddenly. "In 'Taxonomica', Pongosthus divided up magic into eight fields: ritual magic, spell magic, life magic, rune magic, divination magic, artecraft magic, psychic magic, and dwaemer. Dwaemer was everything that hadn't been studied and couldn't be studied. Unconscious, deep, direct magic. Magic without an intermediary, without steps or rules or laws. It's the Old English word for magic, I think."

"Dwaemer," Hermione echoed, without thinking.

"Dwaemer," said Harry, "that fits. You know what, I thought we could do with some rebranding."

"Rebranding?" Ozland said, looking intrigued.

"Sure." He leaned back. "There's no rule against secret societies in Hogwarts, is there?"

Hermione mentally looked through the Hogwarts Rules and came up with nothing. She shook her head.

"Picture this: dark cowls, secret hand signals, spells that look a lot more powerful than they actually are, whispered rumours, blood seeping out from under doors, mystic chants – "

"I feel like I should be doing something about this," said Penelope, not quite under her breath.

"Intimidation isn't just a tool of the powerful," Harry stated. "In the sixties, the Black Panthers wanted to do something about the police randomly terrorising the ghettos. So whenever a police vehicle left the station, they followed in another car, ready with their guns. It worked: when the Panthers were around, the police were too intimidated to do anything. The Panthers could never have confronted every law enforcement agency in the United States head-on – there was an asymmetry in firepower. But what they did understand early on, was that the problem of the police keeping black communities in constant terror couldn't be rectified through superior firepower, but through superior intimidation-power."

"That intimidation-power is backed by fire-power, though," said Ozland, although he was nodding.

"Sure. But if every firearm owned by the police in the United States disappeared for five minutes, for those five minutes the police would still be scary."

"Because they would have tanks. And helicopters."

"Because they would have their glimmering police-badges, their guns in the holsters, their trudgeons, their 'stay calm, mam', their blue uniforms, their white skin, even. They're all symbols of intimidation, of power – symbols that people learn to respect. Pavlovian social cues. Take an ordinary person and decorate him with those symbols, and people still respect him. Maybe he'll even start thinking and acting like an officer. It's all about these," Harry's face went intense, "these unconscious pathways – heuristics – carved out in people's minds that we can manipulate, reconstruct – reversing the direction of intimidation."

Terry frowned. "You were talking about this like it's a war."

"It's helpful to think about it that way. In wars, you have to identify your enemies, your allies, your resources, your constraints, your modes of attack and defense, your higher-level strategies – in other words, muddled thinking won't do. It means you're forced to think clearly, to think about how to win."

Hermione considered this. "What should we call it though? The Muggleborn Dawn?"

"Muggle Struggle?" Ozland suggested.

"No!" Harry looked perplexed. "We're making a secret society not a guerilla army, for heaven's sake. Oh, I see the irony now. Very funny."

"The Syndicate of Esteemed Professionals," Ozland fired off.

"Eighth Echo of the Atlantean Mountain-Crystal," followed Hermione.

Terry had an intense look of thought etched across his face. "Jazuul!" he burst out, triumphantly.

"Too mafia, too Illuminati – Terry, I'm not even sure what you were going for there but it doesn't work. I was more thinking . . . the Bayesian Conspiracy."

"That's a silly name," said Hermione.

"No, it isn't! Look, I'll explain, Bayes was – "

"I know who Bayes was," she said, in what she hoped was a patient tone, "it just doesn't work."

"It's a perfect name. It's literally the guy who formalised an equation for updating beliefs with new information, and then 'conspiracy' slapped onto the end. Progress married to tradition. Openness behind closed doors. Scientific practice fused to ancient lore."

"People won't get it," she said.

"People aren't supposed to get it, and if they open up a book and enlighten – heh – themselves, then all the better."

"The Pentagonal Order," Ozland began tentatively, "the Pentagonal Order of Dwaemercrafters."

"Why pentagonal?" she asked.

"I don't know, something about . . . not being able to tile properly? Look, are we trying to find meaningful names or ones that sound good?"

"The Order of the Midnight Sun," said Kevin, very quietly. "No, hold on, that doesn't make any sense."

"Something with templars in it," suggested Terry.

"The Cabal," Yosif said, simply.

"I like it," admitted Harry. "I really like it. But it needs more."

"The Fifth Cabal," Yosif said. "Then there's the implication that there was a Fourth Cabal before us and we can make up some nonsense about what happened to them."

"I think we're aiming for the wrong thing here," said Ozland slowly. "I think we ought to try for something menacing, but surreal. Like 'The Cult of the Chilled Apricots', or 'Dumbledore's Tantric Love Goblins'."

"The Committee For Eating The Universe," said Harry.

"The Circle of the Eternal Sunshine God," said Hermione, surprising even herself. "I like that one."

"Why," Penelope began, sensibly, "don't you just make six of them and run one secret society each?"

Everyone went silent at this unexpected stroke of genius.

Terry scratched his head. "What, with one member in each? I suppose it'd be secret, but not much of a society."

"No, all of you would be in all of them, but you'd each be the leader of one."

Harry was grinning now. It made Hermione faintly worried. "Why stop at six? I can run two secret societies. Can't everyone else?"

Terry looked horrified. "You're mad. This is all mad. I don't know why it never occurred to me until just now, but all of this is mad and I don't want any part in it."

"Penelope said it best," Harry said, grinning wider than ever, "new students need to stick together."

"I – "

"I'm pretty bloody sure she didn't mean make a bloody cult with shawls! Right, Penelope?"

"Er . . . "

"So, what you're saying is, you don't want to be in the secret clubs all the rest of the Muggleborns are in?" Ozland said, straightfaced.

Terry suddenly looked uncertain. "Um."

"Maybe," said Harry, "you ought to get over your childish antipathy towards shawls. Shawls are a venerable institution of old, you know."

"Hey, it's not the shawls that're the issue here," Terry waved his hands about, "it's, you know, the whole aesthetic associated with shawls. It's silly, if you ask me."

"And ties are just weird pieces of cloth," Harry said, and there was delight in his eyes, "but by the number of businesspeople who wear them, you wouldn't think that, would you?"

"Hold on just one minute," Ozland continued, without giving a chance for Terry to respond, "you're saying a bearded man whisked you away to an invisible dimension inside Britain where he told you you'd been accepted into a school of magic, and now you're inside the school of magic, which is a castle surrounded by forest, and now that we started discussing shawls, now you're saying it's all mad?"

"Do we really have to use shawls?"

"Intimidation-power, not fire-power," said Harry. "Alright, I'm claiming the Committee For Eating The Universe."

Something uneasy was bubbling up inside her. "The Circle of the Eternal Sunshine God for me," said Hermione.

Yosif tilted his head. "The Communist Party of Hogwarts." (Terry snorted.)

"Um," said Ozland, "I'll lead the Invisible Syndicate."

"The Dwaemercrafters Cabal," said Terry.

Kevin shrunk. "I – I don't know. I don't think I want to lead a secret society."

"You have to make a secret society to be in the Secret Society Secret Society," Harry explained. "Otherwise it wouldn't work."

"What Secret Society Secret – " said Terry, who promptly shut-up mid-sentence.

"Oh, alright, then." Kevin sounded oddly breathless. "I'll call it . . . the Secret Police."

The name gave her a strange, heavy sense of foreboding.

"That," said Harry, "is a name worthy of the S.S.S.S. Welcome aboard, Kevin."

"Er, thanks."

"Oh," said Penelope, "I'm not a part of this, am I?"

Harry looked at her sadly. "No, sorry. But if you're in Hogwarts anytime, you're free to join our secret meetings." He paused, pretending to read off of an invisible sheet of paper. "Next on the agenda: what's our secret goal?"

"Hold on, I thought we weren't actually a secret society – " said Terry.

Harry cut him off. "Times have changed, and we must change with the times. The past is ashes and dust, the future stands before us, bright and glorious – "

"The past was four minutes ago – "

"I think we should overthrow the Ministry," Ozland proclaimed, completely seriously.

Hermione opened her mouth, and closed it. "I think we should work within the Ministry to reform it into something better."

"I agree," Yosif said, surprising her. "It's what we did after the 1948 Open-Up Policy. We slowly bought out British and American companies and sabotaged them by organisational reforms. Rearranging departments to cause infighting, assigning employees to the least-optimal jobs, creating new and riskier financial instruments that chained into one another, collecting blackmail material and publishing it to Western audiences to undermine their trust in their own leadership, moving equipment to within Soviet borders . . . it's much more subtle, too."

"Nice infodump. We don't have the resources of the Soviet Union, though," said Harry. "And they still took twenty years."

"We may not be the Soviet Union, but the Ministry isn't the United States, either," remarked Yosif.

"The Ministry isn't going to collapse from inefficiency," Ozland added. "It thrives off of inefficiency. It exists to be inefficient. Ron's dad says there's a drywall regulatory commission for the Office of Self-Referential Office Names – they employ forty people, praise be Matchwell. Overthrowing a government is just reforming it very, very quickly, anyhow."

"The last time someone tried to overthrow the Ministry, a quarter of wizarding Britain died," said Penelope. A hush followed her remark.

"Then we'll do it better. A bloodless coup," Ozland said, heedlessly. "We'll just Imperius all the most important people and see what happens from there."

"The Office of Internal Security runs regular sweeps for mental magics," Hermione countered. "And I doubt any of us could pull off the Imperius Curse. What kind of awful security would the Ministry have to have for a group of teenagers to be able to infiltrate it, anyway?"

"I think we really need a . . . " Ozland wasn't pausing, he was obviously trying to say something but for whatever reason, he couldn't say it. His demeanour became calculating. "Imagine a box that, when opened, prevented all secrets spoken in its vicinity from being spoken about outside of those who had heard it initially. Wouldn't that be something?"

"Oh, a Secret Box, you mean?" asked Penelope.

"Yes," Ozland said, seeming relieved. "Does anyone know where to buy a Secret Box?"

Nobody did.

"I don't intend to overthrow, dehegemonise, or conduct a protracted struggle against the Ministry or any of its affiliates," said Harry, suddenly. "All discussion on my part is purely hypothetical and in the interest of helping the Ministry establish better security protocols. I won't ever involve myself in an anti-Ministry organisation, anything I say to the contrary following or preceding this statement is in pure jest." And then, in a lighter tone: "Hermione, why don't you tell us about Veritaserum?"

She was confused. "It's a potion which forces the drinker to tell the truth. One drop – oh, I see. Um, one drop makes the drinker more truthful, but doesn't compel them. Two drops makes them tell the truth, but gives them leeway in which parts of it they disclose. Three drops makes them spill out the entire truth. The truth, nothing but the truth, and the whole truth. Also, what Harry said. The Ministry is great, yaddah yaddah."

Ozland looked contemplative, and then the same thought struck him, too – she could see it. "I don't intend to do any of those things either. I, too, discuss these matters in jest."

Penelope caught on soon afterward. "As a Ministry employee and a respectable witch who has listened to their conversation so far, I believe that neither Harry, Hermione Granger, nor Ozland Cunningham are the sort of people who would do illegal things like overthrowing the Ministry or wanting to overthrow the Ministry in the first place."

Terry was utterly confused. "What what what?"

Yosif smiled wanly. "I concur with Penelope's observations and believe that everything that has been said so far is true and authentic. I, similarly, have no wish to undermine the unquestionable authority of the Ministry of Magic and strongly condemn those who do. All hail the Ministry."

"All hail the Ministry," Kevin repeated.

"Can someone tell me what the hell is going on?"

Everyone looked at each other uneasily. Harry spoke first. "Say someone had to testify under Veritaserum about a conversation. Maybe the interrogator is asking about what people said – "

"What, so you're only saying all of this so if the Ministry hauls us in – "

"Shut up," suggested Ozland. "Shut up right now or I'll tear your guts out, tie them into a pretzel, and put them back inside your body." It was an absurd and heavy-handed threat, but there was something intimidating about the way he spoke that made Hermione think he'd find something else less absurd but just as painful and do that instead. Seeing her stare at him, she could have sworn he winked, but when she looked again, there was no trace of levity in his face.

Terry paled. "Oh. What I was going to say was: so you're only saying all of this so if the Ministry hauls us in . . . "

"So if the good and fine Ministry brings us in for questioning for whatever reason, we will be able to be perfectly truthful with them," Harry continued, smoothly. "Yes, Ozland, I'll see if I can get myself a Secret Box for my own purposes as a private citizen, as is my right under Ministry law, which it is very important not to break. On a totally unrelated note, perhaps we should arrange for lessons in Occlumency, which assists with protecting against mental intrusion."

"That's a good idea," Ozland said stiltedly. "In the meanwhile, we should focus on the real purpose of the Secret Society Secret Society, which is to amend Wizengamot law, allowing Muggleborn students to enroll in Hogwarts in their First Year."

"Yes, the real purpose," she muttered.

Ozland leant forward. "The whole business with estranged wizards – and witches," he corrected himself, "I'm not sure if there's a gender-neutral word in common use – "

"Mages," Hermione said without thinking.

"Mages," Ozland acknowledged, "the whole business with estranged mages – that's the term for it, I remember now – starting in Fifth Year, it's bullshit, isn't it? What the hell was the Wizengamot thinking when they made that policy?"

By the vigorous nods from around the circle, this seemed to be a very popular sentiment.

"Bullshit," Terry Boot said, recovering quickly from his earlier terror. He repeated 'bullshit' a few more times, turning it into a gloomy mantra. "You heard Al," (he's calling Althea 'Al'?, Hermione thought, incredulously) "how could anyone be expected to catch up with four years worth of magic?"

"That's the point," Harry said, "we're not supposed to be able to. It's obvious from a game-theoretic standpoint." He opened his mouth, as if he was about to continue, but seemed to consciously stop himself, to think for a moment. "There's a book in the Hogwarts Library in the north-north-west shelf," he started. "It lists each result for each exam for every student before 1977. Now," he held up his hand in a conciliatory gesture, "I haven't gone through the whole thing myself. But, Jorgan Perrault did, and wrote a paper on his findings – and this is the exact number – he found that Muggleborns score an average of 5.4 points higher on exams. Once you remove Muggle Studies from the dataset, it comes down to 2.2 points. Would anyone like to hazard a guess as to why I'm bringing this up?"

"What," Terry said, "you thinking the Wibblegambit, er, Wizardgimblet – ah, fuck it, one made-up word is as good as another – you think they deliberately crippled – "

"Is it because we have more of a motivation to study?" Penelope said. "We don't have any property or connections or wealth in the wizarding world, so that means Muggleborns compensate through working harder . . . ?" she trailed off.

Harry held up a finger. "Perrault suggested a few reasons why that might be the case, including that, but it's not why I'm mentioning the study. The Perrault study caused a major internal rift within, well, calling them the anti-Muggleborn faction would be reductionist, but they don't have a name for themselves – for that matter, I don't think they don't even think of themselves as a faction, really," he added, pensively, "but anyhow, it caused a fair deal of trouble for them, challenging ideological preconceptions and whatnot. It was impossible for any sane person to reject the paper as Muggleborn propaganda. Perrault was a pureblood and even he was surprised by his own findings, and it's based in data that just about anyone can access. The Perrault study was undeniable. They didn't want to change their maps, so they changed the territory."

This remark received many confused looks.

Harry shook his head, as if remonstrating himself. "They had a belief, which was that Muggleborns are inferior in terms of magical performance to purebloods due to the impurity of their bloodlines, and a reality that didn't fit. So they changed reality so it did."

The room was quiet for a moment as everybody absorbed the implications of what Harry had said.

"That's brilliant, really," Ozland said. "And I suppose it didn't need any grand conspiracy either, just rich toffs deciding to vote in favour to spite Dumbledore and his people, I'd think."

...

...

Hermione heard the click of a mechanical stopwatch. Harry held it up by its chain and examined it. "Fifteen minutes of conversation without a single awkward pause," he said. "My fault for bringing up something so esoteric. Alright, let's go around. Kevin?"

"Pass."

Terry also passed.

"Hermione?"

"Ozland, you said you were involved in paragovernmental affairs."

"I wanted to follow up on that, too," Harry admitted. "It sounded very plot-hook-y."

"What's there to say?"

"You know," Harry said, "which paragovernment. In what way you're involved. Those sort of things."

"Um. Is anyone here an Unorthdoxist?"

Harry's eyes shone with suppressed amusement. He held up a finger. "Oh, no. This is perfect. Don't tell me. You unintentionally used dwaemer once and people thought it was a miracle and now you're some sort of Messianic politico-religious figure."

"You really figured all of that out from a single question?"

"No, your face was on the Express the other day and the article went into it. The rest is just familiarity with literary tropes – I couldn't put my finger on it until you asked."

"For the benefit of the people who haven't read that particular issue of the Express," Hermione said (and there was a little part of her that was ashamed to admit she hadn't read something), "who is Ozland, exactly?"

"He's the leader of a cult-mafia-junta thing," said Harry, looking absolutely overjoyed for some reason, "produces half the illegal drugs in the Pacific, major black market trafficker, massacres and tortures his opponents, has nuclear weapons, brainwashes his people with quack religious doctrine. At least, that's what the Express thinks. Ozland, care to comment?"

"I wouldn't expect anyone living in the opulent metropole of Britain to understand." Ozland stared off distantly, over her head. She knew it was theatre, but it didn't make it any less effective. "The Celestian Unorthodox Church fills social voids. As a spiritual organisation, we provide hope to the hopeless. As a paragovernment, we create order out of disorder. As a network of public and private enterprises, we give the needy what they need. Drugs? Caffeine, alcohol, and tobacco are drugs, sure-as-hell, and I don't see any moral outrage directed at coffee beans. Legality isn't morality, Harry.

"Human trafficking? We help people get from A to B. We're an intercontinental bus service, making safe passage for families crossing oceans to get one step closer to their dreams. We oil the machine of demand and supply and assist with economic recovery. Brainwashing? In our schools, we provide a free education not only in science and mathematics, but in love, kindness, and respect. Is any of that so bad?"

"And nuclear weapons?" Hermione asked.

"I think every country deserves the right to its own sovereignty, Hermione. Conventional militaries are expensive. Wouldn't you rather that money be spent on helping the poor and treating the ill? Without a nuclear-response system, every nation is a sitting duck, ready to be shot down by the British Empire."

"Massacring and torturing your opponents, then?"

"Puerile war-propaganda. We work with our opponents. We believe in synthesis, not antithesis. In diplomacy, the Church builds bridges, not bombs."

Hermione sat back. There was something oddly enthralling about seeing the truth spun so boldly. "You really are . . . wow."

"I know," Ozland smiled thinly, "I'm not that persuasive when you put me on the spot, though. All of those things are things I've had to respond to over the years, so I suppose you could say it's a prepared spiel."

"Do you believe it?" Penelope questioned.

"I don't know. It's not really that important."

Althea strutted into the room. "Meet-and-greet is over, folks. Hermione, Harry, Terry, Kevin, if you run, you'll be able to catch the eleven o'clock from Hogsmeade to King's Cross. Yosif, the Hedge should take you to the Kirghiz Embassy. Ozland, Professor McGonagall's office, ASAP."

##

"So," said Harry. "Mind telling me the truth?"

Messing around with gravity was the final middle-finger that wizarding Britain had delivered to the mundane universe. Sure, the Levitation Charm had been around since the mid-sixteenth century at the very latest (U. Pin-de-Éare, 'Conquering Gravity'), but actually changing the direction and magnitude of gravity within a given space hadn't been perfected until 1956. Maybe, Hermione thought, the gravityless nature of the corridor of the train wasn't just a pointless gimmick, but had some sort of indecipherable reasoning behind it.

The compartment was rather large, and since Harry had insisted that Terry and Kevin find a different compartment, it was much too large for comfort with only the two of them sitting there.

All of these thoughts flashed through her head as she opened her mouth.

"Well," she said, "that would take a very long time, Harry Potter."

#######

THE DEPARTMENT OF MYSTERIES – FEBRUARY 2, 1931

There was a centre, there was always a centre.

The Head Unspeakable watched, distantly, as molten stone sloughed off onto the floor. A powerful ritual had been conducted here. An imperfect ritual, evidently. The floor itself looked as if some malevolent god had taken an eggbeater to the granite foundations. It still swirled subtly, never quite settling, like a cyclone.

And in the eye of the cyclone . . .

The Head Unspeakable had a staff. All wizards who mattered a damn had staffs, even if they denied it. His looked a bit like a totem pole with a thousand intricate, monstrous faces etched in. It gleamed with gold.

The Head Unspeakable used the staff to prod the head of Reginald Rookwood, who was lying, face-down, in the centre.

Rookwood groaned. He turned over. He blinked three times, and then jumped a bit when he saw the Head Unspeakable looming over him.

"What," said the Head Unspeakable, "were you trying to do?"

"Um," said Reginald, "promise you won't get angry?"

#######

LEVEL MINUS TWENTY-EIGHT – TWENTY YEARS LATER

"As you can see," the Unspeakable explained as they came down the spiral staircase, "the leylines are humming along quite nicely. New ones are opening up every day."

"Ah, these must be the special leylines," Dumbledore said.

"How do you mean, sir?"

"These leylines glow brightly, emerging from a single point," continued Dumbledore, kindly. "They must be very special leylines, indeed, to diverge so much from their cousins, who are nigh imperceptible to the unaided eye, only trace the contours of the Earth, and can be passed through without harm – unlike these, I hear."

"Of course," replied the Unspeakable, hoping that his voice wasn't wavering, "naturally. Ah, very well-observed, sir. These are artificial leylines, after all. A different beast entirely."

There was a cracking sound. Before he could react, a triangular fragment of reality flew at them. The Unspeakable ducked. Dumbledore caught it between thumb and forefinger.

The Unspeakable turned, aghast, seeing the hole it had left behind. Violent, golden light spilled out into the room. Dumbledore walked forward to the hole, and neatly plugged it up.

His face was grim. "A different beast entirely," he said. "The Head Unspeakable and I have many things to discuss, it seems."

#######